<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<title>Great Day Atlantic City News</title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news</link>
<description>Great Day Atlantic City News</description>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Career Exploration Took Center Stage at Sovereign Avenue School’s Annual Fair
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/career-exploration-took-center-stage-at-sovereign-avenue-schools-annual-fair</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble and Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Sovereign Avenue School brought careers to life with its April Career Fair, featuring K-9 demos, EMT tours, and industry professionals.
From law enforcement to DJing, students explored inspiring career paths and heard real-world success stories.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">Sovereign Avenue School</strong> hosted a vibrant and engaging <strong id="">Career Fair</strong> on <strong id="">April 11, 2025</strong>, offering students a firsthand look at a variety of professional paths. Organized by <strong id="">Assistant Principal Bonnie Lynch</strong> and <strong id="">Principal Nicole Williams</strong>, the event was designed to broaden students’ perspectives and introduce them to careers beyond the traditional classroom curriculum.</p><p id="">The day featured several exciting presentations, including a standout <strong id="">K-9 demonstration</strong> by the <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Department</strong>. Officers <strong id="">Mike Braxton Jr.</strong> and <strong id="">Dooley Brent</strong>, along with their canine partners <strong id="">Ryker</strong> and <strong id="">Jax</strong>, showcased how dogs assist in suspect apprehension and <strong id="">bomb detection</strong>, captivating students with real-world examples of law enforcement in action.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:593px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="593px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/68068d7906d24364d5bf9474_489928971_1204146431715107_2225150569712649246_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Students also engaged with representatives from <strong id="">AtlantiCare Emergency Medical Services</strong>, who provided insight into the lifesaving roles of <strong id="">EMTs</strong>. <strong id="">Battalion Chief Dan DeMarco</strong> and <strong id="">EMT Chris Trench</strong> led an interactive ambulance tour and answered student questions, emphasizing the importance of emergency response work.</p><p id="">The fair offered even more inspiration with appearances from <strong id="">engineers</strong>, a <strong id="">hair stylist</strong>, and local DJ <strong id="">Jayln Harris</strong>—known professionally as <strong id="">DJ Jay</strong>—who spoke about turning a passion for music into a successful career. Students explored <strong id="">prosthesis technology</strong> with the engineers and learned how creativity and technical skills can shape exciting professions in various fields.</p><p id="">The event wrapped up with an empowering message from DJ Jay: “<strong id="">If you decide you want to do something, the only thing stopping you is yourself</strong>.” The <strong id="">Sovereign Avenue School Career Fair</strong> succeeded in motivating students to dream big and explore the many possibilities their futures may hold.</p><p id="">‍</p><p>Photo submitted by: <strong>Atlantic City Public Schools</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/career-exploration-took-center-stage-at-sovereign-avenue-schools-annual-fair</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/68068d69f1c657b51d5480b9_491543473_1204146568381760_8146395288562213438_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Volunteers Came Together to Beautify Midtown During April’s Adopt A Block Cleanup
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/volunteers-came-together-to-beautify-midtown-during-aprils-adopt-a-block-cleanup</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Midtown volunteers gathered for a beautiful morning of cleaning and community at the April Adopt A Block event.
Participants worked together to revitalize the neighborhood and were rewarded with lunch and community pride.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">It was a <strong id="">beautiful morning</strong> in Midtown as volunteers gathered for the April edition of the <strong id="">Adopt A Block</strong> community cleanup. Residents, local leaders, and volunteers joined forces to help refresh and revitalize the neighborhood, showing their pride and commitment to keeping Atlantic City clean and welcoming.</p><p id="">Organized by the Midtown office, the cleanup drew community members of all ages who contributed their time and energy to picking up litter, sweeping sidewalks, and making Midtown shine. The event not only improved the physical appearance of the area but also fostered a stronger sense of unity and collaboration among participants.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/680686b680fe3f94559419a2_491441772_17931941355012796_3814838553798240771_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Everyone who took part played a meaningful role in promoting civic responsibility and setting an example for others to follow. Following the cleanup, volunteers were treated to a <strong id="">lunch</strong> as a thank-you for their hard work and dedication.</p><p id="">Those who missed this month’s cleanup were encouraged to join the next one, scheduled for <strong id="">May 10th at 10 AM</strong>, meeting at <strong id="">1809 Pacific Ave</strong>. The initiative remains a great way to give back and connect with fellow residents.</p><p>‍</p><p>Photo Submitted by: <strong>Midtown Atlantic City CDC</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/volunteers-came-together-to-beautify-midtown-during-aprils-adopt-a-block-cleanup</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/680686a742bd6a073206a033_490472280_17931941364012796_2336135914652901759_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Council Honors Student Athlete and Special Events Team for Outstanding Achievements
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-council-honors-student-athlete-and-special-events-team-for-outstanding-achievements</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[City Council honored Khajuan “Peaky” Roseborough for his record-breaking performance in sports and strong academics, and recognized the Mayor’s Office of Special Events for their standout work on the Aquarium Grand Reopening.
Both were celebrated as shining examples of excellence and dedication in Atlantic City.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">During the most recent <strong id="">City of Atlantic City - Government City Council</strong> meeting, Council members formally recognized <strong id="">Khajuan “Peaky” Roseborough</strong>, a standout member of the <strong id="">Atlantic City High School Class of 2025</strong>, for his exceptional achievements both on and off the field. Roseborough not only broke records in <strong id="">football</strong> and <strong id="">basketball</strong>, but also maintained an impressive <strong id="">3.5 GPA</strong>, exemplifying the balance of athletic excellence and academic dedication.</p><p id="">City Council praised Roseborough’s commitment to his education while excelling as a student-athlete, calling him a role model for young people throughout the city. His recognition marked a proud moment for Atlantic City High School and the broader community.</p><p id="">In addition, Council commended the <strong id="">Mayor’s Office of Special Events</strong> for their outstanding work organizing major city functions. The team was especially lauded for their stunning decorations and logistical coordination during last month’s <strong id="">Atlantic City Aquarium Grand Reopening</strong>, which drew praise from residents and visitors alike.</p><p id="">Their efforts were described as vital to the city’s continued success in hosting vibrant, well-executed public events that highlight Atlantic City’s unique character and culture.</p><figure class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/680683321c49754cb707e2ca_492010852_988700080111128_1857106740072083009_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit"></div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-council-honors-student-athlete-and-special-events-team-for-outstanding-achievements</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/68068322be01934429c7f6bc_491831683_988700060111130_3940598556278357689_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Mayor Small Highlights Crime Reduction at NOBLE Region I Conference in Atlantic City
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-highlights-crime-reduction-at-noble-region-i-conference-in-atlantic-city</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Mayor Small and Chief Sarkos addressed national law enforcement leaders at the NOBLE Region I Conference, celebrating an 11-percent drop in crime in Atlantic City.
The conference showcased the city's recent public safety successes and its growing role in regional law enforcement leadership.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Mayor <strong id="">Small</strong> and Atlantic City Police Department Chief <strong id="">Sarkos</strong> were among the featured speakers at the National Organization of Black Law Enforcement Executives (<strong id="">NOBLE</strong>) Region I Conference, held at the <strong id="">Hard Rock Hotel &amp; Casino Atlantic City</strong>. The event brought together law enforcement leadership from across the country for a week of collaboration, dialogue, and strategic planning.</p><p id="">During his address, Mayor <strong id="">Small</strong> officially welcomed the distinguished guests and emphasized the importance of unity and innovation in public safety. He also took the opportunity to spotlight the progress being made locally, including a notable <strong id="">11-percent decrease in crime</strong> during the first quarter of 2025 compared to the same period in 2024.</p><p id="">Mayor <strong id="">Small</strong> praised the Atlantic City Police Department for its proactive efforts and commitment to community policing, crediting the decrease in crime to strategic partnerships and data-driven approaches. Chief <strong id="">Sarkos</strong> also underscored the department’s dedication to transparency and ongoing reform efforts aimed at building public trust.</p><p id="">The presence of national law enforcement leaders, combined with the celebration of Atlantic City’s local achievements, made the conference a meaningful moment of recognition and forward momentum for the city.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-highlights-crime-reduction-at-noble-region-i-conference-in-atlantic-city</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/680680f67a20fc93be641fcf_491833893_988564193458050_3870851947765200822_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Crime Continues Downward Trend in 2025, First Quarter Data Shows
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-crime-continues-downward-trend-in-2025-first-quarter-data-shows</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The City of Atlantic City is seeing real progress in public safety. According to newly released data from the Atlantic City Police Department (ACPD), overall crime in the city has dropped by more than 11% in the first quarter of 2025 compared to the same period in 2024—another strong signal that the Small administration’s investments in safety and technology are delivering results.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The City of Atlantic City is seeing real progress in public safety. According to newly released data from the Atlantic City Police Department (ACPD), overall crime in the city has dropped by more than 11% in the first quarter of 2025 compared to the same period in 2024—another strong signal that the Small administration’s investments in safety and technology are delivering results.</p><p id="">The statistics, sourced from the New Jersey State Police Offense Report, show declines across every major crime category:</p><ul id=""><li id=""><strong id="">Crimes Against Persons</strong> (including homicide, assault, and sex offenses) are down <strong id="">22.28%</strong></li><li id=""><strong id="">Crimes Against Property</strong> (including robbery, burglary, and theft) have decreased by <strong id="">4.3%</strong></li><li id=""><strong id="">Crimes Against Society</strong> (including drug offenses, weapons offenses, and prostitution) are down <strong id="">4.48%</strong></li></ul><p id="">In total, Group "A" Offenses fell from 1,427 in Q1 2024 to 1,266 in Q1 2025—an <strong id="">11.28% decrease</strong> overall.</p><p id="">Perhaps most significantly, there were <strong id="">zero homicides reported in the first quarter of 2025</strong>, compared to six during the same time last year. Non-fatal shooting incidents are also down. The ACPD investigated <strong id="">just three shooting cases in 2025</strong>, versus eight similar incidents in early 2024—a <strong id="">62.5% reduction</strong>.</p><p id="">“There's this exaggerated narrative that Atlantic City is not clean and safe, but the facts and data tell a different story,” said Mayor Marty Small, Sr. “The Atlantic City Police Department keeps showing why they are the best police department in the world. Whether it’s added manpower, new equipment and technology, or promotions, my administration will continue to support law enforcement in every way possible to keep this downward trend in crime going.”</p><p id="">ACPD responded to <strong id="">24,733 calls for service</strong> in the first quarter of 2025—averaging 274 calls per day. That’s a notable decrease from the 26,523 calls for service during the same period in 2024. Arrest totals have remained steady: 1,159 individuals were charged in Q1 2025, nearly identical to last year’s 1,161. However, <strong id="">juvenile arrests have increased</strong>, rising from 36 in 2024 to 67 in 2025.</p><p id="">Ongoing initiatives like the <strong id="">Citywide Surveillance Camera Project</strong>—now two-thirds complete—are strengthening the city’s crime-fighting tools. New surveillance cameras are coming online each week, improving real-time response, crash analysis, and officer safety.</p><p id="">In addition, the <strong id="">Casino Reinvestment Development Authority (CRDA)</strong> has awarded a <strong id="">$3 million grant</strong> to expand patrols in the Tourism District through March 2026. Beginning April 1, increased police presence on the Boardwalk and surrounding areas will include five new utility terrain vehicles (UTVs), complementing bicycle and foot patrols for greater visibility and coverage.</p><p id="">“I am excited about the progress we’ve made in the first quarter of 2025 and the future improvements ahead,” said ACPD Chief James A. Sarkos. “With the ongoing hard work and commitment of our officers, our partnerships with the city and community, and the integration of new technologies, I am confident that we will continue to reduce crime and make a lasting impact on public safety in Atlantic City.”</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-crime-continues-downward-trend-in-2025-first-quarter-data-shows</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ebf6b21f9a78736bc01ca1_488015396_975172011463935_7854978879748047333_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Mayor Small Unveils 2025 Budget with Continued Tax Reduction and Investor Confidence for Atlantic City
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-unveils-2025-budget-with-continued-tax-relief-and-investor-confidence</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City is charting a new course—and delivering real results. This week, Mayor Marty Small Sr. announced the sixth consecutive property tax decrease for Atlantic City residents, cementing a powerful trend of financial responsibility and resident-focused governance. Unveiled during a news conference at City Hall, the 2025 City of Atlantic City budget includes a 3.4-cent tax rate reduction—a move that not only keeps money in residents’ pockets, but also sends a clear message: this administration is putting people first.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id=""><em id="">Six straight years of tax decreases reflect strong leadership, community investment, and growing economic momentum.</em></strong></p><p id="">Atlantic City continues to chart a new path forward—one defined by fiscal responsibility, transparency, and a deep commitment to the people who call it home. This week, Mayor Marty Small Sr. announced the sixth consecutive municipal property tax decrease, part of a $258 million city budget that prioritizes both community needs and long-term financial strength.</p><p id="">The 3.4-cent tax rate cut in the 2025 budget follows years of strategic planning and disciplined budgeting under the Small administration, and is a clear reflection of the city’s core focus: putting residents first while ensuring Atlantic City is a place where families can thrive, businesses can grow, and investors can feel confident.</p><p id="">“This administration is keeping its promise by making the city’s taxpayers its number one priority,” Mayor Small shared during a news conference at City Hall. “Once again, Atlantic City is a leader when it comes to fiscal responsibility.”</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Real Relief, Strategic Spending</strong></h3><p id="">The 2025 budget includes $258 million in municipal spending, and when including grant funds, totals nearly $280 million. The budget also includes a full payoff of the city’s debt service for the year—a move made possible by years of careful financial management.</p><p id="">According to Chief Financial Officer Toro Aboderin, the city now holds a $78 million surplus, $28 million of which will be used to fund the 2025 budget. The budget also allocates $27 million toward capital improvements, including street paving and building repairs—delivering visible, on-the-ground benefits to Atlantic City residents.</p><p id="">Perhaps even more remarkable: the city’s outstanding debt has dropped from $550 million in 2019 to $328 million today, showing how far the city has come since state oversight began under the 2016 Municipal Stabilization and Revitalization Act.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">State Support Driving Down the Levy</strong></h3><p id="">One key piece of Atlantic City’s financial turnaround has been its access to Investment Alternative Taxes (IATs)—taxes collected from casino gaming revenues that are now used to help pay down municipal debt. In 2024, the city received over $68 million in IAT funding, thanks to reforms that redirected these revenues from the CRDA back into the city’s general operations.</p><p id="">As a result, Atlantic City’s tax levy has plummeted—from $128 million in 2015 to just $34 million today. Meanwhile, the tax collection rate has improved from roughly 95% in 2019 to 98.1% in 2025—a testament to growing public trust and consistent city leadership.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Credit Ratings and Investor Outlook on the Rise</strong></h3><p id="">This momentum has not gone unnoticed. In September, Moody’s Ratings upgraded the city’s long-term issuer rating to Ba2, while Standard &amp; Poor’s raised its rating to BB+. Atlantic City is now just one step away from investment-grade status—a critical milestone that could unlock new funding opportunities and strengthen the city’s ability to attract developers and anchor institutions.</p><p id="">Mayor Small and his finance team, including Business Administrator Anthony Swan, Budget Officer Tom Monoghan, and partners from the Department of Community Affairs, say they are laser-focused on keeping the progress going.</p><p id="">“We’re continuously finding ways to get more money and make our financial situation better,” Small said. “With the plethora of development projects scheduled to come online next year, we’re going to be in a great place to have another tax decrease.”</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Why It Matters</strong></h3><p id="">For residents, six years of steady tax relief means Atlantic City is becoming a more affordable place to live and raise a family. For businesses and entrepreneurs, it signals smart, stable governance and ongoing investment in infrastructure, safety, and growth. And for investors watching from afar, it’s another reason to believe in Atlantic City’s transformation.</p><p id="">From balancing budgets to backing bold development initiatives like Bader Field, Mayor Small’s administration is demonstrating what it means to lead with both fiscal discipline and a community-first vision.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-unveils-2025-budget-with-continued-tax-relief-and-investor-confidence</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/68008a30ef52407f79c633b4_ACBudget09.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Planning with Purpose: Atlantic City Seniors Gained Insight at Lunch & Learn Session
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/planning-with-purpose-seniors-gained-insight-at-lunch-learn-session</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The second Lunch & Learn Session of 2025 brought seniors together for an informative presentation on Wills, Trusts, and Estate Planning, led by Anne Crozier of the Bratton Law Firm. Attendees left informed, inspired, and full of both knowledge and lunch.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">Atlantic City Senior Services</strong> successfully hosted its second <strong id="">Lunch &amp; Learn Session</strong> of 2025, offering residents valuable knowledge in a relaxed and welcoming setting. The event was designed to provide both educational enrichment and a sense of community for seniors.</p><p id="">The featured speaker, <strong id="">Anne Crozier</strong> of the <strong id="">Bratton Law Firm</strong>, led a highly informative discussion focused on <strong id="">Wills</strong>, <strong id="">Trusts</strong>, and <strong id="">Estate Planning</strong>. Her presentation helped attendees better understand their options for preparing and protecting their assets, and sparked thoughtful questions from the audience.</p><p id="">The session offered more than just information—it encouraged open dialogue and empowered participants to consider their long-term plans with greater clarity. The interactive nature of the event allowed for real-time <strong id="">questions and answers</strong>, ensuring that everyone left with a deeper understanding of the topics discussed.</p><p id="">Following the presentation, attendees enjoyed a <strong id="">wonderful lunch</strong>, shared conversations, and built stronger connections with one another. The event reflected the mission of Atlantic City Senior Services to not only inform, but also uplift and connect the senior community.</p><p id="">It was a meaningful afternoon filled with practical guidance and personal warmth—proof that learning is lifelong, and so is the value of friendship and community support.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/planning-with-purpose-seniors-gained-insight-at-lunch-learn-session</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffe35a8baa6bc8a4ba43a4_489127681_537124259430543_2894202450794408558_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Seniors Enjoyed a Cake Decorating Experience
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/sweet-moments-atlantic-city-seniors-enjoyed-a-cake-decorating-experience</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City seniors enjoyed a creative afternoon of cake decorating, bringing smiles, frosting, and fun to the community. The event was part of ongoing senior services activities offered by the City.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">City of Atlantic City – Government</strong> recently hosted a fun and flavorful event for local seniors: a <strong id="">cake decorating</strong> activity designed to bring joy, creativity, and community engagement to residents aged 55 and older.</p><p id="">Participants tapped into their artistic sides while enjoying hands-on guidance in designing and decorating their own sweet creations. The event was filled with laughter, conversation, and a shared appreciation for the simple joy of trying something new.</p><p id="">The initiative was part of the city’s ongoing commitment to <strong id="">Atlantic City Senior Services</strong>, which provides meaningful, engaging, and accessible activities for the community’s older adults. From social events to wellness programs, these efforts aim to keep seniors connected and active.</p><p id="">This cake decorating day was more than just a tasty outing—it was a chance for seniors to gather, create, and celebrate the value of community and lifelong learning.</p><p id="">Additional <strong id="">senior services</strong> programs were planned throughout the month, offering residents continued opportunities to enjoy enriching and interactive experiences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/sweet-moments-atlantic-city-seniors-enjoyed-a-cake-decorating-experience</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffdf68cc9071bfc672ac8d_490383286_984195090561627_4331906551282806182_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Bringing Health to the Heart of the Community: Baltic Plaza Health Fair Recap
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/bringing-health-to-the-heart-of-the-community-baltic-plaza-health-fair-recap</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Community Health Fair at Baltic Plaza brought residents and healthcare providers together for a day of support and wellness. Thanks to community partnerships, essential health resources were made accessible to the people of Atlantic City.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services hosted a successful Community Health Fair at Baltic Plaza, where residents gathered for a day dedicated to wellness, connection, and empowerment. The event aimed to bring vital health resources directly to the community in an accessible and supportive setting.</p><p id="">A wide range of services and information were provided thanks to the collaboration with AtlantiCare, Southern Jersey Family Medical Centers, Inc., and the Cape Atlantic Coalition for Health. These partners played a key role in delivering on-site screenings, health education, and personalized guidance to attendees of all ages.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1390px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1390px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffdbf13d06635e0f4475e4_Screenshot%202025-04-17%20003151.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Residents had the opportunity to speak directly with healthcare professionals, learn about preventative care, and receive materials on maintaining long-term wellness. The fair fostered a welcoming atmosphere where people felt seen, heard, and cared for—underscoring the importance of community-driven public health efforts.</p><p id="">The event also created space for conversations around health equity and access, aligning with the City’s mission to make wellness resources more inclusive and available to all Atlantic City residents.</p><p id="">By the end of the day, new relationships were formed, knowledge was shared, and a stronger sense of community health was established. It was a powerful reminder that public health is most impactful when it meets people where they are.</p><p>‍</p><p>Photos submitted by: City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/bringing-health-to-the-heart-of-the-community-baltic-plaza-health-fair-recap</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffda4a957e925746a92b6c_490209481_683256817713701_1657020895956941223_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Public Safety Academy at Atlantic City High School Announced 2025 Expansion
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/public-safety-academy-at-atlantic-city-high-school-announced-2025-expansion</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Public Safety Academy at Atlantic City High School was set to expand in 2025, offering more career pathways in fire, police, and emergency services. Launched in 2019 and temporarily paused during the pandemic, the program prepared students for real-world roles in public safety.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The Public Safety Academy at Atlantic City High School was announced to expand in 2025, creating even more career-focused opportunities for students interested in public service fields. This initiative continued the school's commitment to preparing students for real-world careers through hands-on learning and mentorship.</p><p id="">Originally launched in 2019, the academy had been temporarily paused due to the challenges brought by the COVID-19 pandemic. Despite the interruption, the program remained a vital part of the school’s vision for student success and community involvement.</p><p id="">The academy gave students direct access to experienced professionals from the Atlantic City Fire Department, Police Department, Beach Patrol, and Emergency Medical Services. These partnerships allowed students to gain valuable insight into the demands and rewards of careers in public safety.</p><p id="">The upcoming expansion was expected to broaden the curriculum and bring in additional resources, ensuring that students receive the most relevant training and exposure to various emergency response fields. With the relaunch, more students would have the chance to explore career pathways in service roles that directly impact their communities.</p><p id="">This announcement reaffirmed Atlantic City High School’s role in shaping future leaders and responders through education, access, and opportunity.</p><p id="">The <strong id="">Public Safety Academy at Atlantic City High School</strong> was announced to expand in 2025, creating even more career-focused opportunities for students interested in public service fields. This initiative continued the school's commitment to preparing students for real-world careers through hands-on learning and mentorship.</p><p id="">Originally launched in <strong id="">2019</strong>, the academy had been <strong id="">temporarily paused</strong> due to the challenges brought by the COVID-19 pandemic. Despite the interruption, the program remained a vital part of the school’s vision for student success and community involvement.</p><p id="">The academy gave students direct access to experienced professionals from the <strong id="">Atlantic City Fire Department</strong>, <strong id="">Police Department</strong>, <strong id="">Beach Patrol</strong>, and <strong id="">Emergency Medical Services</strong>. These partnerships allowed students to gain valuable insight into the demands and rewards of careers in public safety.</p><p id="">The upcoming expansion was expected to broaden the curriculum and bring in additional resources, ensuring that students receive the most relevant training and exposure to various emergency response fields. With the relaunch, more students would have the chance to explore career pathways in service roles that directly impact their communities.</p><p id="">This announcement reaffirmed Atlantic City High School’s role in shaping future leaders and responders through education, access, and opportunity.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:600px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="600px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffcd087fd7d05983f56017_491414049_18223012633293165_1154101108641892899_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos Submitted by: <strong id="">Atlantic City High School</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/public-safety-academy-at-atlantic-city-high-school-announced-2025-expansion</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffccf7cc077562e821e0b0_490070919_18223012630293165_3193021743290185654_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City High School Environmental Club Collaborated with Public Works for Campus Cleanup
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-high-school-environmental-club-collaborated-with-public-works-for-campus-cleanup</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Atlantic City High School Environmental Club joined forces with the Public Works Department for a successful cleanup outside the school. This effort marked a strong start to the city’s upcoming Clean Communities initiative.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">City of Atlantic City Government</strong> recently expressed gratitude to the <strong id="">Atlantic City High School Environmental Club</strong> for their collaboration with the <strong id="">Public Works Department</strong> during a successful cleanup effort outside the school. The event demonstrated the power of community partnerships and youth involvement in environmental stewardship.</p><p id="">This cleanup was part of the city's ongoing commitment to keeping neighborhoods clean and green. Students from the Environmental Club worked alongside city staff to clear debris and beautify the area around their campus. Their dedication and teamwork were a testament to the positive impact young residents can make when given the opportunity to lead.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:600px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="600px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffcb2666ebcc43cfecea4d_490226957_982541010727035_3663718340253444784_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The initiative served as a preview of the city’s upcoming <strong id="">Clean Communities</strong> campaign, an annual program aimed at encouraging civic pride and environmental responsibility through organized cleanup events.</p><p id="">The City is excited to continue these efforts in the months ahead, building on the success of this recent collaboration and engaging even more community groups and volunteers.</p><p id="">By working together, Atlantic City continues to foster a cleaner, more sustainable future for all residents.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos submitted by: <strong id="">Atlantic City High School Environmental Club</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-high-school-environmental-club-collaborated-with-public-works-for-campus-cleanup</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ffcb2f2911b7a6ca2fc56e_489991019_982541017393701_1984922262933171758_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Inspiring Champions: Matchroom Boxing and Jaron “Boots” Ennis Visit the Club
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/inspiring-champions-matchroom-boxing-and-jaron-boots-ennis-visit-the-club</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble and Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Matchroom Boxing and Jaron “Boots” Ennis inspired the youth of Atlantic City with a powerful visit to the Boys & Girls Club during fight week.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City, in collaboration with Jim Whelan Boardwalk Hall, recently welcomed a powerful visit from Matchroom Boxing and Jaron “Boots” Ennis during fight week. Their presence brought a surge of energy and encouragement to Club members, showing firsthand what dedication and belief in one's dreams can achieve.</p><p id="">Jaron “Boots” Ennis, a standout in the boxing world, spent time connecting with the youth, sharing his story, and urging them to follow their dreams and never stop reaching for their goals. His words served as a reminder that greatness begins with vision and commitment.</p><p id="">Adding an exciting twist to the visit, Golden Gloves VR gave Club members the chance to step into the ring—virtually. The immersive virtual reality boxing experience sparked joy, laughter, and curiosity, leaving a lasting impact on the youth as they got a taste of the sport in a whole new way.</p><p id="">This unforgettable event highlighted the importance of community support and positive role models. It emphasized how powerful real-world experiences and motivational figures can be in shaping the aspirations of young minds.</p><p id="">The week concluded with a thrilling public event at Caesars Atlantic City Hotel &amp; Casino, where supporters gathered for the official weigh-in on Friday at 6 PM.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/inspiring-champions-matchroom-boxing-and-jaron-boots-ennis-visit-the-club</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f7dcb591ad4015bfaf79f4_490353335_1111955507637578_3025438720853137515_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Inspiring Voices: Aneesha DuBois Visits the Boys & Girls Club
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/inspiring-voices-aneesha-dubois-visits-the-boys-girls-club</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble and Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Boys & Girls Club of Atlantic City had a fun and empowering visit from Passport Poppy and Aneesha DuBois, who spoke about Character and Commercial Voiceovers while inspiring our youth to follow their dreams.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City recently welcomed <strong id="">Passport Poppy</strong> and <strong id="">Aneesha DuBois</strong> for an engaging and uplifting visit with our Club Members. The experience turned out to be not only <strong id="">fun</strong>, but also deeply <strong id="">inspirational</strong>, leaving a lasting impact on the youth who participated.</p><p id="">During her time with the Club, Aneesha DuBois encouraged members to <strong id="">follow their dreams</strong> and to believe in their own unique paths. Her message resonated with the young attendees, many of whom left the event feeling motivated and seen.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:600px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="600px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f56071b0d394ed9b2ad560_489130706_1110016137831515_8954389017764117_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">She also took time to speak about <strong id="">Character</strong> and <strong id="">Commercial Voiceovers</strong>, opening the door to exciting possibilities in creative and performance-driven careers. Her real-world insight and encouragement showed the members that success comes in many forms, and that perseverance and personality are key ingredients.</p><p id="">The event served as a meaningful reminder of the power of mentorship and representation. The Boys &amp; Girls Club is proud to continue offering opportunities like this that help shape confident, goal-oriented leaders of tomorrow.</p><p>‍</p><p>Photos submtted by: Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/inspiring-voices-aneesha-dubois-visits-the-boys-girls-club</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f56065f422b4d6380ef0fb_489067743_1110016084498187_2623878563785269478_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Teen Club Members Embraced Growth Mindset and Family Empowerment
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/teen-club-members-embraced-growth-mindset-and-family-empowerment</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble and Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Teen Club Members at the Boys & Girls Club of Atlantic City engaged in a powerful Growth Mindset session focused on Family Empowerment, taking an inspiring step toward personal development and stronger family connections.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Teen Club Members</strong> of the <strong id="">Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City</strong> took a meaningful step toward personal development and community connection through a dynamic <strong id="">Growth Mindset</strong> session. This impactful experience was designed to reinforce the power of positive thinking, resilience, and self-belief.</p><p id="">Centered on the theme of <strong id="">Family Empowerment</strong>, the session encouraged youth to reflect on their roles within their families and how mindset can shape both personal and collective growth. Teens were inspired to unlock their potential while strengthening bonds at home.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f55ddef422b4d6380c7243_488643089_1104685211697941_3856940204678520916_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The environment fostered encouragement, open dialogue, and goal-setting, reinforcing the Club’s commitment to nurturing not only strong individuals but also stronger families. Participants walked away with strategies to face challenges with confidence and a renewed sense of purpose.</p><p id="">By embracing the values of <strong id="">Growth Mindset</strong> and <strong id="">Family Empowerment</strong>, the Boys &amp; Girls Club continued its mission of building <strong id="">strong minds and brighter futures</strong> for the youth of Atlantic City.</p><p>‍</p><p>Photos submitted by: Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/teen-club-members-embraced-growth-mindset-and-family-empowerment</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f55dd6e8b0b586a93fbf4f_488408047_1104685205031275_9006093982698987074_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Main Library Marked April with Poetry, Autism Awareness, and a Book Sale
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-main-library-marked-april-with-poetry-autism-awareness-and-a-book-sale</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Atlantic City Main Library marked National Library Week with a $5 book bag sale, a heartfelt Poet Tree for National Poetry Month, and a special display for Autism Acceptance Month—bringing education, creativity, and community together.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Visitors to the <strong id="">Atlantic City Main Library</strong> during <strong id="">National Library Week</strong> (April 6–12) were welcomed by vibrant and meaningful displays that highlighted multiple April observances. A special <strong id="">book sale</strong> invited patrons to fill a library drawstring bag with as many books, CDs, and DVDs as they could fit—all for just $5.</p><p id="">In honor of <strong id="">National Poetry Month</strong>, the library introduced a creative “<strong id="">Poet Tree</strong>” project. Guests were encouraged to write poems on paper leaves, reflecting on why they love Atlantic City. These heartfelt pieces were then added to a growing display that celebrated the voices of the community.</p><p id="">The library also recognized <strong id="">Autism Acceptance Month</strong> with a curated book display, thoughtfully assembled by staff to encourage understanding and inclusion. This highlighted the library’s commitment to offering educational and inclusive resources to the public.</p><p id="">Throughout the week, the library buzzed with activity and engagement, offering residents of all ages a chance to learn, reflect, and express themselves while celebrating the joys of reading and community connection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-main-library-marked-april-with-poetry-autism-awareness-and-a-book-sale</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f55c27d1d47ada96e0305e_489304782_1070158648479208_8145670806997377920_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Inaugural Daddy Daughter Sneaker Ball Brings Families Together in Atlantic City
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-night-to-remember-atlantic-citys-first-daddy-daughter-sneaker-ball</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The City of Atlantic City held its first Daddy Daughter Sneaker Ball, where proud dads and beaming daughters shared a night full of joy, dancing, and unforgettable memories. Organized by AC Rec and city partners, the evening was truly magical.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><em id="">A new tradition focused on family, connection, and community pride.</em></p><p id="">When Mayor Marty Small Sr. took office in 2019, he made a promise to create more opportunities for families to come together, celebrate one another, and feel connected to the city they call home. That promise was on full display at Atlantic City’s All Wars Memorial Building during the inaugural Daddy Daughter Sneaker Ball, an event that many hope will become a new Atlantic City tradition.</p><p id="">Organized by the Atlantic City Recreation Division, the Sneaker Ball was a refreshing twist on the traditional father-daughter dance—offering an experience that prioritized fun, fashion, and family. The free event welcomed fathers and father figures from across Atlantic City to attend with their daughters, walking the red carpet, posing for photos, and dancing the night away in outfits that mixed formal flair with comfortable sneakers.</p><p id="">Inside the beautifully decorated venue—thanks to the Mayor’s Office of Special Events—guests enjoyed dinner, desserts, “mocktails,” and giveaways donated by generous local businesses and community partners. These touches reinforced the heart of the event: community support and connection.</p><p id="">While the Recreation Division is known for its sports leagues and youth programs, events like this reflect its broader mission to create meaningful moments that bring people together. Recreation Director Mike Griffin shared that more events like this are already being planned, in addition to the division’s ongoing after-school programming and seasonal trips designed to keep Atlantic City youth active, inspired, and engaged.</p><p id="">Since the Mayor’s first term, Atlantic City has continued to invest in programming that brings joy, promotes unity, and helps families create memories close to home. These types of initiatives speak to a broader goal—making Atlantic City a place where people can thrive, raise their families, find opportunity, and take pride in where they live.</p><p id="">The success of the first-ever Daddy Daughter Sneaker Ball proves that Atlantic City residents are ready to celebrate one another in new ways—and that the city is just getting started. These moments of joy and connection are what make Atlantic City a great place to live, work, and invest.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id=""><strong id="">Want more good news in your inbox?</strong>‍</p><p id="">‍<strong id="">Sign up for the Great Day Atlantic City newsletter</strong> to stay up to date on events, progress, and community wins that showcase the best of Atlantic City.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-night-to-remember-atlantic-citys-first-daddy-daughter-sneaker-ball</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f75761b131fbe53d1a8542_Screenshot%202025-04-10%20012956.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Senior Services Enjoys a Day of Bargain Hunting and Tradition
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-senior-services-enjoys-a-day-of-bargain-hunting-and-tradition</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Senior Services took seniors on a joyful trip that combined a first-time visit to the Red White and Blue Thrift Market with a return to the familiar Berlin Market. The day was filled with fun, friendship, and great deals.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">Atlantic City Senior Services</strong> embraced both the excitement of something new and the comfort of the familiar during a special shopping outing. Participants made their first visit to the <strong id="">Red White and Blue Thrift Market</strong>, exploring a new destination filled with unique finds and unbeatable prices.</p><p id="">In addition to this new adventure, the group also returned to a beloved favorite—the <strong id="">Berlin Market</strong>—a place filled with memories and familiar vendors. This blend of new and old provided the seniors with an enriching experience full of connection, nostalgia, and discovery.</p><p id="">The day was filled with laughter, shared stories, and plenty of <strong id="">great deals</strong>, as everyone enjoyed browsing through treasures and scoring bargains. Whether it was a vintage gem or a fresh find, the excitement of the hunt brought joy to all who joined.</p><p id="">This outing reflected the mission of Atlantic City Senior Services to keep seniors engaged, active, and socially connected through meaningful experiences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-senior-services-enjoys-a-day-of-bargain-hunting-and-tradition</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f5550e3a180598b9c5e9b1_487715986_531679529975016_7835982449347693842_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Girl Scouts Strengthen Mind and Body Through Yoga and Basketball
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-girl-scouts-strengthen-mind-and-body-through-yoga-and-basketball</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble and Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Girl Scouts in Atlantic City boosted their focus and teamwork during a special session that paired yoga with basketball drills. The event empowered participants both mentally and physically, thanks to Atlantic City Youth Services.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">Atlantic City Youth Services</strong> recently hosted an engaging and empowering session for local <strong id="">Girl Scouts</strong>, blending physical activity with mindfulness. The event combined <strong id="">yoga for focus</strong> and <strong id="">basketball drills for teamwork</strong>, offering participants a unique experience that nurtured both mental clarity and physical coordination.</p><p id="">The <strong id="">yoga</strong> portion of the day helped the girls center themselves, promoting balance, calmness, and improved concentration. In a world full of distractions, this practice provided tools to help the young participants build emotional resilience and inner strength.</p><p id="">Following the mindfulness session, the girls jumped into <strong id="">basketball drills</strong> designed to boost communication, cooperation, and leadership. These exercises emphasized the importance of working together, encouraging the scouts to support one another on and off the court.</p><p id="">This dynamic activity day not only promoted healthy habits but also fostered confidence and unity among the participants. The event reflected the ongoing mission of Atlantic City Youth Services to uplift youth through meaningful, character-building experiences.</p><p>‍</p><p>Photos and Videos are submitted by: &nbsp;Atlantic City Youth Services</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-girl-scouts-strengthen-mind-and-body-through-yoga-and-basketball</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f5420047b971be1c332e39_488595218_17998061213774785_611911977198266398_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
The Laff House Opens with Laughter and Celebration at ACX1 Studios Atlantic City
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/the-laff-house-opens-with-laughter-and-celebration-at-acx1-studios-atlantic-city</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Laff House at ACX1 Studios launched with a successful opening night, celebrated by Mayor Small and city officials during a ribbon cutting. The venue adds new energy to Atlantic City's comedy and entertainment scene.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">The Laff House at ACX1 Studios</strong> officially opened its doors in Atlantic City, marking its debut with a lively and laughter-filled opening night. This exciting new venue brought comedy to the forefront of the city’s entertainment scene, offering a fresh space for performers and audiences to connect through humor.</p><p id="">The grand opening event was highlighted by a <strong id="">ribbon cutting ceremony</strong>, where <strong id="">Mayor Marty Small</strong> and representatives from the <strong id="">City of Atlantic City - Government</strong> were in attendance to show their support and celebrate the new addition to the city’s cultural landscape.</p><p id="">As a welcome addition to <strong id="">ACX1 Studios</strong> and the broader Atlantic City arts community, The Laff House is expected to draw comedy lovers from across the region. The venue adds a dynamic new layer to the city’s entertainment offerings and creates more opportunities for creative expression.</p><p id="">With a strong start and warm community reception, The Laff House promises to become a beloved space for both local and visiting comedians to share their talent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/the-laff-house-opens-with-laughter-and-celebration-at-acx1-studios-atlantic-city</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f541685bb2e98d97268963_488022728_976810511300085_1652136213000324520_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Recreation Hosts Action-Packed Fun Day for Local Youth
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-recreation-hosts-action-packed-fun-day-for-local-youth</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Eric Rembert</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Recreation’s FUN DAY gave local youth a chance to play, learn, and connect during their school break. The event was just one of many free programs supported by AC Rec and Atlantic City Youth Services.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Atlantic City Recreation's <strong id="">FUN DAY</strong> event, held at the <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Athletic League Inc. Building</strong>, brought excitement and energy to the community yesterday. The event offered a lively break for kids who were off from school, providing a space to engage in games, sports, and creative activities in a safe and welcoming environment.</p><p id="">The building buzzed with laughter and movement as children enjoyed everything from <strong id="">basketball</strong> to <strong id="">board games</strong>, making the most of their day off. The initiative created an opportunity for social interaction and physical activity, all while promoting positivity and community spirit.</p><p id="">This event was part of a broader effort by <strong id="">AC Rec</strong> and <strong id="">Atlantic City Youth Services</strong> to provide free, enriching activities for local youth. Their continued collaboration ensures that young residents have access to meaningful programs throughout the year.</p><p id="">April and the months ahead are packed with more opportunities for youth engagement, with even more <strong id="">free activities</strong> planned to keep kids active, creative, and connected to their community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-recreation-hosts-action-packed-fun-day-for-local-youth</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f53c97adafcca3a50199b7_488034942_976062634708206_5210793755030263413_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Celebrates Community Leaders at Women’s Empowerment Luncheon
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-celebrates-community-leaders-at-womens-empowerment-luncheon</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tre' Smith</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Local leaders were honored during Atlantic City’s Women’s Empowerment Luncheon, where community, culture, and financial literacy took center stage. The event recognized impactful women and fostered a spirit of inspiration and unity.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The City of Atlantic City recently celebrated <strong id="">Women’s History Month</strong> with a heartfelt Women’s Empowerment Luncheon on Saturday, March 29, 2025. Hosted by the <strong id="">Mayor’s Office of Special Events</strong>, the gathering brought the community together in a sea of purple to honor local women making a difference.</p><p>‍</p><figure class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f53a473a2eb4e49668fbd5_487440534_975958244718645_3005700364296603204_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit"></div></figure><p id="">Among those recognized were <strong id="">Henrietta Shelton</strong>, President and CEO of the Chicken Bone Beach Historical Foundation, Inc., and <strong id="">Kiyia Harris</strong>, Strategic Community Program Coordinator in the City’s Community Block Development Grant (CDBG) Office. Both women were acknowledged for their outstanding contributions and unwavering dedication to the Atlantic City community.</p><p id="">The event featured <strong id="">Bashira Khan</strong> as the guest speaker, who delivered an insightful presentation on <strong id="">financial literacy</strong>, offering attendees valuable knowledge on saving and smart money habits.</p><p id="">Alongside the honors and speeches, the luncheon included vibrant <strong id="">dancing</strong> and a fun <strong id="">raffle</strong>, creating a festive atmosphere filled with empowerment and connection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-celebrates-community-leaders-at-womens-empowerment-luncheon</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67f539fa1b390ee199b9ad64_487715990_975957738052029_4005327858344488317_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Honoring Dedication: Atlantic City Police Promotions and New Officer Appointment
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-dedication-atlantic-city-police-promotions-and-new-officer-appointment</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Atlantic City Police Department proudly promoted four officers to Sergeant and welcomed a new Special Law Enforcement Officer, Class II during a ceremony led by Mayor Small. This momentous occasion honored the dedication, leadership, and service of these officers as they stepped into their new roles to better serve the community.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Department</strong> recently celebrated the achievements of its officers by promoting four distinguished police officers to the rank of <strong id="">Sergeant</strong> and welcoming a new <strong id="">Special Law Enforcement Officer, Class II</strong>. The promotional ceremony, led by <strong id="">Mayor Small</strong>, recognized the unwavering commitment, leadership, and dedication of these officers to serving and protecting the community.</p><p id="">During the event, the department honored <strong id="">Albert Herbert, Corey Treadway, Eric Wessler,</strong> and <strong id="">Patrick Yarrow</strong>, who earned well-deserved promotions to <strong id="">Sergeant of Police</strong>. Each of these officers demonstrated exceptional dedication, professionalism, and leadership throughout their careers, making them valuable assets to the department. Their promotions reflected their ability to take on greater responsibilities, mentor fellow officers, and contribute to the department’s mission of maintaining safety and order in Atlantic City.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67ebf6b21f9a78736bc01ca1_488015396_975172011463935_7854978879748047333_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">In addition to the promotions, the department welcomed <strong id="">Jason Pike</strong> as a <strong id="">Special Law Enforcement Officer, Class II</strong>. This position plays a crucial role in assisting full-time officers and ensuring public safety. Officer Pike’s appointment marked an important addition to the force, reinforcing the city’s commitment to effective law enforcement and community protection.</p><p id="">The ceremony served as a moment of pride for the officers, their families, and the entire department, highlighting the dedication and perseverance required to achieve such milestones. Law enforcement is a challenging profession that demands integrity, courage, and continuous learning. These newly promoted sergeants and the newly appointed officer exemplified these qualities, earning the trust and respect of their colleagues and the community they serve.</p><p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Department</strong> remains steadfast in its mission to recognize and reward excellence within its ranks. By promoting and appointing skilled officers, the department ensures that the highest level of service, leadership, and protection is provided to the residents and visitors of Atlantic City.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-dedication-atlantic-city-police-promotions-and-new-officer-appointment</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/68026bffa79968bc60c03c12_67ebf5cee67640045101674e_488080516_975172031463933_8071828285159051874_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Honoring Small Businesses: Atlantic City Celebrates National Mom and Pop Business Owners Day
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-small-businesses-atlantic-city-celebrates-national-mom-and-pop-business-owners-day</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City celebrated National Mom and Pop Business Owners Day on March 29, 2025, highlighting the importance of small businesses and the entrepreneurs behind them. The day also recognized the participants of the Small Business Academy, a FREE city program dedicated to helping residents start and grow their own businesses.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">On March 29, 2025, <strong id="">Atlantic City</strong> proudly recognized <strong id="">National Mom and Pop Business Owners Day</strong>, celebrating the hardworking entrepreneurs who form the backbone of the local economy. Residents and visitors alike were encouraged to show their support by shopping at <strong id="">small businesses</strong> throughout the city, reinforcing the importance of local commerce and community-driven success.</p><p id="">Among those honored were the dedicated participants of the <strong id="">Small Business Academy</strong>, a <strong id="">FREE</strong> program offered by the <strong id="">City of Atlantic City</strong> to equip aspiring entrepreneurs with the knowledge and tools needed to <strong id="">start and grow their own businesses</strong>. The academy plays a crucial role in fostering the next generation of business owners, helping them navigate the challenges of launching and sustaining a successful enterprise.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67eaaaab80a470fe3bf8e5f4_486695933_972822005032269_6372598890021979427_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">“The <strong id="">Small Business Academy</strong> is more than just a program—it’s an investment in the future of Atlantic City,” said Mayor Marty Small Sr. “By providing resources, mentorship, and hands-on education, we are empowering residents to build thriving businesses that contribute to our city’s economic vitality.”</p><p id="">Participants of the <strong id="">Small Business Academy</strong> gain insight into business planning, financial management, marketing strategies, and customer engagement. Many graduates of the program have gone on to open storefronts, online ventures, and service-based businesses, further strengthening Atlantic City's entrepreneurial landscape.</p><p id="">As Atlantic City continues to uplift its small business community, programs like the <strong id="">Small Business Academy</strong> ensure that passionate entrepreneurs have the support they need to turn their dreams into reality. The city remains committed to fostering a business-friendly environment where local enterprises can flourish for years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-small-businesses-atlantic-city-celebrates-national-mom-and-pop-business-owners-day</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67eaaa9e660533fcb387fcf9_486851470_972822061698930_6260257751214553182_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City’s Safety Data Improves as Officials Target Public Perception Gap
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-citys-safety-data-improves-as-officials-target-public-perception-gap</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Recent data shows crime continues to decline in Atlantic City, prompting city and state leaders to focus efforts on reshaping outdated public perceptions.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Atlantic City’s commitment to becoming a safer, stronger community is yielding tangible results, with city officials actively working to ensure these improvements are recognized and felt throughout the community.</p><p id="">According to a recent article by <strong id="">John O’Connor in </strong><a href="https://pressofatlanticcity.com/news/local/crime-courts/article_ee5f5376-da06-48fc-9ece-ee380b708ea8.html?utm_campaign=snd-autopilot&utm_medium=social&utm_source=facebook_The_Press_of_Atlantic_City&fbclid=IwY2xjawJT2LpleHRuA2FlbQIxMQABHXhURNHDgSpQHdK2Vj7Yjm1Gaky2sH9aC9vuI9XULZiNDim3cfpsGo08GA_aem_phrOdEDZn8lrHWCQF8PPIg" id=""><strong id=""><em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em></strong></a>, data presented by Police Chief James Sarkos indicates that crime decreased by 8.6% in 2024, with an additional <strong id="">19.19% reduction</strong> observed in the first quarter of 2025. Calls for service have also declined by over 9% compared to the same period last year, and more than 170 arrests have been made in the past two weeks alone.</p><p id="">City and state leaders are collaborating to ensure these advancements contribute to a broader shift in public perception. As <em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em> reports, officials from the Department of Community Affairs are coordinating communications with the city’s Public Safety Director Sean Riggin, the Police Department’s Public Information Office, and community-based partners to disseminate information about the city's progress.</p><p id="">The message is clear: Atlantic City is safer, cleaner, and more united than ever. However, reshaping outdated perceptions requires continuous effort. Local leaders recognize that for every negative headline, there are numerous untold stories about neighborhood revitalization, family-friendly activities, walkable communities, and strong community-police partnerships.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Strategic Investments Enhancing Community Safety</strong></h3><p id="">These improvements are the result of deliberate initiatives. In his <a href="https://youtu.be/2ybNtjk-74U" id=""><strong id="">2025 State of the City address</strong></a>, <strong id="">Mayor Marty Small Sr.</strong> detailed several proactive measures undertaken to enhance public safety and improve residents' quality of life.</p><p id="">Key initiatives include:</p><ul id=""><li id=""><strong id="">Increased police patrols</strong> in high-traffic areas such as Atlantic and Pacific Avenues, the Boardwalk, and Renaissance Plaza to ensure a visible and reassuring presence.</li><li id="">The near completion of a <strong id="">citywide surveillance camera system</strong>, enhancing real-time monitoring and deterrence capabilities.</li><li id="">The continuation of the <strong id="">Clean Communities program</strong>, now in its fourth year, focusing on neighborhood beautification and cleanliness to foster community pride.</li><li id="">Upgrades by the <strong id="">Department of Public Works</strong>, including the acquisition of new Madvac cleaning vehicles, a street sweeper, and improved snow emergency equipment to maintain safe and clean public spaces.</li><li id="">Infrastructure improvements such as <strong id="">paving projects on Baltic Avenue and Martin Luther King Jr. Boulevard</strong>, with upcoming work on Atlantic Avenue aimed at improving accessibility and pedestrian safety.</li></ul><h3 id=""><strong id="">Community Observations and Evolving Perceptions</strong></h3><p id="">Residents are noticing these positive changes. As highlighted by <em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em>, individuals in neighborhoods like<strong id=""> </strong>Chelsea have observed a visible transformation. One community leader noted an increase in people, including women, walking comfortably at night—a subtle yet significant indicator of progress.</p><p id="">Nonetheless, city officials understand that <strong id="">changing perception takes time</strong>. Therefore, communication efforts are being prioritized alongside physical improvements to ensure that both residents and visitors not only experience enhanced safety but also understand the comprehensive vision driving Atlantic City’s transformation.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Looking Forward</strong></h3><p id="">Atlantic City’s leadership remains dedicated to sustaining this positive trajectory by aligning public safety, infrastructure, community development, and communication efforts within a cohesive strategy.</p><p id="">The data is compelling. The initiatives are in motion. The partnerships are robust. Now, the focus is on ensuring that the public narrative accurately reflects the on-the-ground reality.</p><p id=""><strong id="">Crime is decreasing. Community confidence is rising. Perceptions are evolving. Atlantic City is progressing.</strong></p><p id="">‍</p><h3 id="">Read the original reporting by <em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em>’s <strong id="">John O’Connor</strong> here:<a href="https://pressofatlanticcity.com/news/local/crime-courts/article_ee5f5376-da06-48fc-9ece-ee380b708ea8.html" id=""> </a></h3><p id=""><a href="https://pressofatlanticcity.com/news/local/crime-courts/article_ee5f5376-da06-48fc-9ece-ee380b708ea8.html" id="">Atlantic City's crime rate is dropping. See the numbers.</a></p><p id="">‍</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Watch Mayor Marty Small’s 2025 State of the City Address:</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/2ybNtjk-74U" id=""><strong id=""> </strong></a></h3><p id=""><a href="https://youtu.be/2ybNtjk-74U" id="">YouTube: State of the City 2025</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-citys-safety-data-improves-as-officials-target-public-perception-gap</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6f4b8b2a5947c6990874e_Screenshot%202025-03-28%20151000.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
A Night of Innovation: Chelsea Club’s STEAM Fair Showcased Creativity and Discovery
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-night-of-innovation-chelsea-clubs-steam-fair-showcased-creativity-and-discovery</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Tuesday night STEAM Fair at Chelsea Club was a vibrant showcase of innovation and learning, featuring experiments, botanical LEGO creations, rockets, and more. The community came together to celebrate young minds and their passion for STEAM.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Tuesday night STEAM Fair</strong> at Chelsea Club was an exciting celebration of science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics, bringing together curious minds for an evening of exploration and hands-on learning. Club Members proudly presented their projects, demonstrating their creativity and knowledge in various STEAM fields.</p><p id="">Attendees were amazed by <strong id="">cool experiments</strong>, intricate <strong id="">botanical LEGO creations</strong>, and impressive <strong id="">rockets</strong> launched by the young innovators. Each display highlighted the skills and imagination of the participants, fostering a love for learning and discovery among community members.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6cb26e090f19fabffb19b_487058168_1100191012147361_1509529757354102323_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The event was not only an opportunity to showcase talent but also a space for collaboration and engagement. Families, educators, and community members came together to support and encourage the next generation of thinkers and problem-solvers.</p><p id="">Held at <strong id="">Chelsea Club from 4-6 p.m.</strong>, the STEAM Fair was <strong id="">open to the community</strong>, allowing everyone to experience the wonders of science and creativity. The enthusiasm and passion displayed by the young participants made it a truly memorable event.</p><p id="">As the night ended, the energy and excitement from the fair continued to inspire both participants and guests, reinforcing the importance of STEAM education in shaping the future.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos submitted by: Boys &amp; Girls Club of Atlantic City</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-night-of-innovation-chelsea-clubs-steam-fair-showcased-creativity-and-discovery</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6cb14f34641e31bc81697_487064467_1100191048814024_2242941185379336262_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Residents Embraced Healthy Eating at Second Cooking & Nutrition Class
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-residents-embraced-healthy-eating-at-second-cooking-nutrition-class</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Residents at Atlantic City Townehouse participated in the Second Cooking & Nutrition Class, where they explored the benefits of fruits, practiced kitchen techniques, and enjoyed fresh smoothies. This session emphasized making healthier choices while celebrating the diversity of food traditions.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6bb3b8c9cca3efca8220a_487013928_671227768916606_6748843651878893922_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The <strong id="">City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</strong> hosted its <strong id="">Second Cooking &amp; Nutrition Class</strong> at <strong id="">Atlantic City Townehouse</strong>, bringing residents together for an engaging and educational session on <strong id="">healthy eating</strong>. This week’s class focused on the <strong id="">nutritional benefits of fruits</strong>, encouraging participants to explore new varieties and understand how different cultures incorporate them into their diets.</p><p id="">Residents learned about the essential vitamins, minerals, and antioxidants found in fruits, highlighting their role in promoting <strong id="">overall health and wellness</strong>. The class also provided hands-on learning opportunities, where participants practiced <strong id="">proper knife-handling techniques</strong> to safely cut and prepare fruits. One resident even led a demonstration on the correct way to <strong id="">peel a banana</strong>, showcasing a simple yet important skill for everyday food preparation.</p><p id="">Beyond the technical skills, the class fostered a <strong id="">sense of community and shared learning</strong>. Participants had the chance to connect over their personal experiences with food, exchanging tips and stories about their favorite fruits from different parts of the world. This cultural exchange added depth to the session, reinforcing the importance of a diverse and balanced diet.</p><p id="">‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6bbc7a03ca9f88e07372b_486662880_671227802249936_1175085016033834918_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">To conclude the class, attendees enjoyed a refreshing spread of <strong id="">freshly cut fruits</strong> and homemade <strong id="">fruit smoothies</strong>. The hands-on experience not only reinforced the lessons learned but also provided a delicious and nutritious reward for their efforts. By actively participating in the preparation process, residents gained confidence in making healthier food choices at home.</p><p id="">It was inspiring to see how the knowledge from the class was already being put into action. Many participants expressed their enthusiasm for incorporating more fruits into their meals and continuing to apply their newly acquired skills. The <strong id="">Cooking &amp; Nutrition Class</strong> is proving to be a valuable resource in promoting <strong id="">health-conscious habits, cultural appreciation, and community engagement</strong> in Atlantic City.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos submitted by: City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-residents-embraced-healthy-eating-at-second-cooking-nutrition-class</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e6bb64bd48cb5f619849c1_486678877_671227622249954_8008469700652969066_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
City of Atlantic City Secures $10.3M to Complete Paving and Safety Enhancements on Atlantic Avenue
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/city-of-atlantic-city-secures-10-3m-to-complete-paving-and-safety-enhancements-on-atlantic-avenue</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City has secured full federal funding to begin the long-awaited revitalization of Atlantic Avenue, with major paving and safety improvements set to start this summer.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The long-anticipated transformation of Atlantic Avenue is officially moving forward. Mayor Marty Small Sr. announced on March 26, 2025, that the City of Atlantic City has secured the final $10.3 million in federal funding needed to launch the next phase of the Atlantic Avenue Safety Improvement Project—a major infrastructure initiative that will improve travel, safety, and accessibility through the heart of the city.</p><p id="">The funding, released through a RAISE (Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity) Grant, comes with the support of <strong id="">Congressman Jeff Van Drew</strong>, who played a key role in moving the project forward.</p><p id="">“This grant is a huge step forward for Atlantic City and all of South Jersey,” Congressman Van Drew shared in a statement. “It will help fund crucial improvements to Atlantic Avenue, including repaving the roadway, better synchronization of streetlights, and enhanced safety measures. It will not only improve safety for residents and visitors alike, but also have a significant impact on the economic development of Atlantic City.”</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">What’s Coming to Atlantic Avenue</strong></h3><p id="">The Atlantic Avenue Safety Improvement Project will deliver critical upgrades from <strong id="">Tennessee to Albany Avenues</strong>, including:<br>- Full <strong id="">repaving</strong> of Atlantic Avenue<br>- <strong id="">Synchronized traffic signals</strong> for smoother travel<br>- <strong id="">LED street lighting</strong> to enhance visibility and safety<br>- <strong id="">New wayfinding signage</strong> for better navigation<br>- <strong id="">Improved sidewalks, curbs, and ADA-accessible ramps</strong><br>- Added safety features at key intersections</p><p id="">This work follows the successful completion of the first phase of the project, completed at the end of 2023, which covered paving, lighting, and signal synchronization from Maine to Tennessee Avenues. The groundwork was also laid for smart infrastructure through the installation of fiber and conduit from Tennessee to Albany Avenues.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Next Steps Toward Completion</strong></h3><p id="">The City is now awaiting authorization to bid from the New Jersey Department of Transportation (NJDOT). Once granted, bidding will open this spring, with contracts anticipated to be awarded in May 2025. If all goes as planned, construction and paving will begin and be completed by the end of the summer.</p><p id="">Mayor Marty Small Sr. called the moment “a major victory for the residents, visitors, and future developers in the great City of Atlantic City.” He added, “We’re incorporating an aggressive construction schedule to get this done as quickly and as safely as possible.”</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Safer Streets, Stronger Future</strong></h3><p id="">Atlantic Avenue has long been known as one of the most dangerous roads in South Jersey, and these improvements aim to turn that reputation around. With pedestrian safety, accessibility, and connectivity as key priorities, this revitalization will benefit not just drivers, but the entire community.</p><p id="">“This project is the result of years of hard work,” Van Drew added. “By revitalizing the businesses and infrastructure along this corridor, we’re helping to strengthen the very heart of our community.”</p><p id="">The Atlantic and Pacific Avenue improvements—totaling $24.8 million—are funded through a combination of federal and state investments.</p><p id="">As Atlantic City continues to rise with infrastructure investments, the Atlantic Avenue project reflects a broader vision: a safer, smarter, more vibrant city—built to serve both residents and visitors alike.</p><p id="">Stay tuned to <a target="_new" href="http://www.GreatDayAtlanticCity.com" id="">GreatDayAtlanticCity.com</a> for project updates.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/city-of-atlantic-city-secures-10-3m-to-complete-paving-and-safety-enhancements-on-atlantic-avenue</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e4e63cccadca3655f78ca5_Screenshot%202025-03-27%20014612.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Public Schools Elementary Swim Program Earns Third Place in First Competitive Meet
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-elementary-swim-program-earns-third-place-in-first-competitive-meet</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Public Schools Elementary Swim Program proudly secured third place in its first-ever competitive meet, setting the stage for young swimmers to pursue bigger opportunities.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Public Schools Elementary Swim Program</strong> recently achieved an impressive <strong id="">third-place finish</strong> in its <strong id="">first-ever competitive swim meet</strong>, marking a significant milestone for the young athletes.</p><p id="">The meet, hosted at <strong id="">Atlantic City High School</strong>, brought together students from <strong id="">Absecon</strong> and <strong id="">Brigantine</strong> school districts. Designed to teach elementary students essential swimming skills, the program also serves as a <strong id="">feeder</strong> to the high school swim team — preparing the next generation of Atlantic City swimmers.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e424cebd391940a400756e_486767585_1182139290582488_8691076756563499929_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id=""><strong id="">Elementary Swim Coach Kellie Hornbaker</strong> expressed pride in the team’s performance. “We’re still building the depth of the team and focusing on making swimming exciting for the kids,” Hornbaker said. “Our main goal was to ensure they understood how a swim meet works — and that they had fun doing it.”</p><p id="">The program operates in partnership with the <strong id="">Brigantine Aquatics Center (BAC)</strong>, where <strong id="">Coach Lanise Graves</strong> worked closely with the students. Graves emphasized the transformative power of swimming, noting that many participants began the program without knowing how to swim. “To see them now, winning medals, is incredible,” she said. “We pushed them hard, and they never gave up.”</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e424e5de83879dbfd92fb4_486609556_1182139060582511_7824063079999623388_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id=""><strong id="">Robin Taylor</strong>, owner of <strong id="">Brigantine Aquatics</strong>, highlighted the broader impact of the program, noting that it helps Atlantic City students access local opportunities. <strong id="">Donald Harris</strong>, Director of Secondary Education, praised the initiative’s alignment with a national push to expand swim programs in urban communities. “This is about more than swimming — it’s about changing the narrative,” Harris said. “Our kids are proving that they belong in the water, too.”</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-elementary-swim-program-earns-third-place-in-first-competitive-meet</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e424c3f9b5baaf438a1e5e_486747973_1182139087249175_6522808946894361179_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City's Multicultural Services Host First Tai Chi Class
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-calm-and-centered-start-first-tai-chi-class-at-community-haven</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services hosted its first Tai Chi class at Community Haven, offering participants an introduction to this gentle, meditative practice focused on balance, relaxation, and mindfulness. The class set a calm and promising tone for the upcoming sessions.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</strong> successfully hosted its <strong id="">first Tai Chi class</strong> at <strong id="">Community Haven</strong>, in collaboration with <strong id="">IMUSA</strong>. The session introduced participants to this <strong id="">gentle and meditative practice</strong>, focusing on <strong id="">breathing techniques</strong>, <strong id="">stretches</strong>, and the <strong id="">foundations of Tai Chi</strong> — all aimed at promoting <strong id="">balance</strong>, <strong id="">relaxation</strong>, and <strong id="">mindfulness</strong>.</p><p id="">Students embraced the experience, discovering how Tai Chi combines <strong id="">movement and breath</strong> to create a sense of <strong id="">inner calm and physical stability</strong>. The class offered a welcoming environment where everyone could <strong id="">slow down</strong>, <strong id="">reconnect with their bodies</strong>, and <strong id="">release tension</strong> from their day.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1391px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1391px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e2c90edf212b2840efe5a8_Screenshot%202025-03-25%20231320.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The first class marked an <strong id="">energizing and peaceful start</strong> to the series, leaving participants feeling <strong id="">relaxed and refreshed</strong>. The blend of <strong id="">gentle stretches</strong> and <strong id="">focused breathing</strong> provided a glimpse into the <strong id="">healing potential</strong> of this <strong id="">centuries-old practice</strong>.</p><p id="">This successful launch set the stage for <strong id="">upcoming sessions</strong>, which promise to <strong id="">dive deeper</strong> into the <strong id="">benefits of Tai Chi</strong>, helping attendees <strong id="">improve their balance</strong>, <strong id="">reduce stress</strong>, and <strong id="">enhance their overall well-being</strong>.</p><p id="">Atlantic City’s <strong id="">Multicultural Services</strong> is looking forward to <strong id="">continuing this journey</strong>, encouraging the community to <strong id="">prioritize both mental and physical wellness</strong> through this <strong id="">accessible and peaceful art form</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-calm-and-centered-start-first-tai-chi-class-at-community-haven</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e2c8eb7f7fea2bdbb242cf_486589181_669025719136811_7720685521053884565_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
A Beloved Treasure Returns: The Atlantic City Aquarium Reopens at Historic Gardner’s Basin
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-aquarium-reopens-after-five-year-hiatus-with-exciting-new-attractions</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[After five years of closure, the Atlantic City Aquarium reopened with a fresh look, exciting new attractions, and interactive exhibits, welcoming guests back to Historic Gardner’s Basin.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">After five years behind closed doors, the <strong id="">Atlantic City Aquarium at Historic Gardner’s Basin</strong> has officially reopened—welcoming residents and visitors back to one of the city’s most treasured attractions.</p><p id="">Following an extensive renovation project that touched nearly every part of the building—inside and out—the Aquarium once again opened its doors this past week with a celebratory ribbon-cutting led by <strong id="">Mayor Marty Small Sr.</strong>, alongside city officials, Aquarium staff, and local stakeholders. Guests were among the first to experience the refreshed space, which hadn’t been open since March 2020.</p><p id="">Originally opened in May 1999, the Aquarium had been closed since the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic. While plans for renovation were already underway before the closure, pandemic-related supply chain delays and the discovery of greater repair needs extended the timeline. But the results are well worth the wait.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">A Fresh Look and New Experiences</strong></h3><p id="">Today, the Aquarium features a new roof, windows, flooring, ceiling decking, renovated bathrooms, updated HVAC systems, lighting, and more. The entire building has been painted, with fresh murals inside and out, and the facility now feels like a brand-new experience.</p><p id="">New exhibits include:</p><ul id=""><li id="">The <strong id="">“Under the Sea” coloring area</strong></li><li id="">A <strong id="">hurricane simulator</strong></li><li id="">A <strong id="">photo booth</strong></li><li id="">And coming early summer: <strong id="">six interactive touch tanks with daily feeding shows featuring bamboo sharks, guitar sharks, mummichogs, grass shrimps, clearnose skates, and cownose rays. </strong></li></ul><p id="">The Aquarium remains home to more than <strong id="">100 fascinating species</strong>, including the star of the show—<strong id="">Groman</strong>, a 225-pound Loggerhead Sea Turtle—as well as diamondback terrapins, rays, seahorses, pipefish, lionfish, and horseshoe crabs.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">A True Community Effort</strong></h3><p id="">The reopening is the result of coordination and commitment across many teams and partners.</p><p id="">The City of Atlantic City’s Public Works Department manages the Aquarium, with Gardner’s Basin Nautical Park Manager Lisa Schall and Aquarist Sarita DuCote-Stroud maintaining the exhibits and property during the closure. Shore Aquarium Services cared for the animals throughout.</p><p id="">The project was led by City Engineer Uzo Ahiarakwe, with Arthur Ponzio Co &amp; Associates serving as project manager. Additional contributions came from:</p><ul id=""><li id=""><strong id="">SOSH Architects &amp; Remington and Vernick Engineers</strong> (consultants)</li><li id=""><strong id="">Weatherby Construction Corporation</strong> (interior renovations)</li><li id=""><strong id="">Shore Building Contractors</strong> (exterior work)</li><li id=""><strong id="">Falasca Mechanical</strong> (HVAC repairs)</li></ul><p id="">The exterior beautification was a true community collaboration. Local artist Kelly Prevard painted new murals on the building’s walls, while youth murals on the second floor were created through a partnership with the City’s Youth Services Division and funded by the Community Development Block Grant.</p><p id="">The Atlantic City Arts Foundation, with sponsorship from the Inlet CDC, installed painted planters featuring artwork by Tabitha Brown, and volunteers from the Atlantic City Hydrangea Trail helped beautify the grounds.</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Open Year-Round for All to Enjoy</strong></h3><p id="">The Atlantic City Aquarium is open <strong id="">seven days a week, from 10 AM to 5 PM</strong>, offering fun and educational experiences for families, school groups, and marine life lovers alike.</p><p id="">Admission information and details about exhibits can be found at <a target="_new" href="http://www.acnj.gov/pages/acaquarium" id="">www.acnj.gov/pages/acaquarium</a> or by calling <strong id="">609-348-2880</strong>.</p><p id="">As Mayor Small shared during the reopening: the Aquarium is more than an attraction—it’s a point of pride. Its return marks another milestone in Atlantic City’s continued growth and commitment to creating experiences that enrich, inspire, and bring joy to all who visit.</p><p id="">‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e2b99c1cb4c5ab7936c4b7_486646832_969923995322070_4732469893555431877_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Guest at the grand opening of the Atlantic City Aquarium <strong id="">(Photo credit:&nbsp;Edward Lea)</strong></p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e2b9c8fe101bcd5464446a_486327543_969923881988748_888559438938608067_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Visitors enjoyed a modernized look and interactive experiences designed for all ages, the Atlantic City Aquarium’s reopening marked an exciting moment for the community and visitors alike. <strong id="">Photo&nbsp;Credit:&nbsp;Edward Lea</strong></p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-aquarium-reopens-after-five-year-hiatus-with-exciting-new-attractions</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67e4ddd7a3a12636c47c3b86_Screenshot%202025-03-27%20011033.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Warm Memories: Atlantic City Seniors Hand Knit Chunky Blankets
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/warm-memories-seniors-hand-knit-chunky-blankets</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Seniors embraced a new adventure with the Third Thursday Craft Program, learning to hand knit chunky blankets — creating warmth, laughter, and beautiful memories.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Today, Atlantic City's Seniors embraced a <strong id="">new adventure</strong> with the <strong id="">Third Thursday Craft Program</strong>. This month’s activity brought creativity and warmth as everyone learned how to <strong id="">hand knit chunky blankets</strong> — a project that was both <strong id="">beautiful</strong> and <strong id="">practical</strong>.</p><p id="">The room was filled with laughter and excitement as seniors explored this new skill. Many shared stories, bonded over the experience, and found joy in seeing their creations come to life.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dd8aaaf58194aa01355f22_485727931_520931034383199_3887772610053411221_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Each blanket was a reflection of personal style and effort, turning soft yarn into cozy masterpieces. The pride in finishing a handmade blanket was clear on everyone’s faces.</p><p id="">This program not only sparked creativity but also fostered <strong id="">connection</strong> and <strong id="">camaraderie</strong> — a reminder that it’s never too late to <strong id="">try something new</strong>.</p><p id="">We’re looking forward to more fun and fulfilling activities in the coming months with our wonderful seniors!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/warm-memories-seniors-hand-knit-chunky-blankets</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dd8a9a24e7147c75551aec_485209109_520930834383219_2622397510764904795_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City's Pennsylvania Avenue School's Black History Month Celebration
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-musical-tribute-pennsylvania-avenue-schools-black-history-month-celebration</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Students at Pennsylvania Avenue School honored Black History Month through music and performance, highlighting the legacy of gospel, R&B, and poetry that shaped African American culture.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Pennsylvania Avenue Elementary School</strong> recently honored <strong id="">Black History Month</strong> with a vibrant celebration centered around music. The event paid tribute to the <strong id="">rich musical heritage</strong> that has shaped African American history and culture, bringing together students, teachers, and the community for an unforgettable experience.</p><p id="">The program opened with a powerful <strong id="">gospel segment</strong>, featuring students singing <strong id="">"Lift Every Voice and Sing,"</strong> often referred to as the <strong id="">Black national anthem</strong>. This emotional start set the tone for the evening, followed by an uplifting performance of <strong id="">"This Little Light of Mine."</strong> Students also shared <strong id="">poetry readings</strong> highlighting iconic figures like <strong id="">Harriet Tubman</strong> and <strong id="">Langston Hughes</strong>, reinforcing the event’s educational significance.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1388px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1388px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dc3552efa00b695dca27ff_Screenshot%202025-03-20%20233350.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">A standout moment was the <strong id="">"Throwback to our Music in History"</strong> segment, where students performed lively lip sync tributes to <strong id="">Boyz II Men</strong> and <strong id="">TLC</strong>, capturing the spirit of these legendary groups. The performances were both nostalgic and enlightening, introducing younger students to influential artists from the past.</p><p id="">The event was led by <strong id="">Dr. Nycole P. Lyles-Belton</strong>, who served as emcee, alongside <strong id="">Elementary School Teacher Shaylyn Neal</strong>, both of whom worked to ensure the program connected students to their cultural roots through music. Lyles-Belton emphasized the importance of celebrating Black music, stating, <strong id="">"Not only does it sound good, but it makes us feel good."</strong></p><p id="">The celebration ended with a powerful <strong id="">group performance</strong> of <strong id="">"We Are the World,"</strong> symbolizing <strong id="">unity, diversity,</strong> and the <strong id="">enduring influence</strong> of African American music. Principal <strong id="">Thomas Biggins</strong> expressed his pride in the students, highlighting how the event encouraged them to recognize the contributions of historical figures and apply those lessons to their own lives.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos submitted by: Atlantic City High School Photography Class</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-musical-tribute-pennsylvania-avenue-schools-black-history-month-celebration</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dc353e4780fbeb9cdb602d_480965340_1176594457803638_2979934378479945291_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Celebrates Holi at Penn Museum’s CultureFest
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-celebrates-holi-at-penn-museums-culturefest</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City residents joined Penn Museum’s CultureFest on March 15th to celebrate Holi — a day filled with music, dance, cultural exhibits, and delicious samosas.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">On <strong id="">Saturday, March 15th</strong>, the <strong id="">City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</strong> brought residents on an unforgettable trip to <strong id="">Penn Museum</strong> to take part in <strong id="">CultureFest</strong>, celebrating the vibrant festival of <strong id="">Holi</strong>. Known as the <strong id="">Festival of Colors</strong>, Holi signifies the arrival of <strong id="">spring</strong>, the power of <strong id="">love</strong>, and the <strong id="">triumph of good over evil</strong> — all celebrated through lively <strong id="">music</strong>, <strong id="">dance</strong>, and <strong id="">colorful gatherings</strong>.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dc1c8e58eeb3b3b15fc17d_485375658_665121452860571_7919908282931744559_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Residents enjoyed an immersive day filled with <strong id="">vibrant performances</strong>, <strong id="">captivating dance showcases</strong>, and <strong id="">fascinating exhibits</strong> that highlighted diverse cultures from around the world. Visitors also explored <strong id="">unique vendors</strong>, discovering <strong id="">special treasures</strong> to bring home as keepsakes from this cultural celebration.</p><p id="">To make the day even more memorable, <strong id="">delicious samosas</strong> were provided for everyone to savor — a delightful touch that brought smiles all around.</p><p id="">Thank you to everyone who joined us for this <strong id="">colorful and enriching</strong> event, celebrating unity, culture, and joy!</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photos submitted by: City of Atlantic City Multicultural Services</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-celebrates-holi-at-penn-museums-culturefest</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dc1c7e48f3efb1065c2ef2_480624262_665123882860328_5391854940347198786_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Youth Witness Hometown Athletes Shine in MAAC Championship
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/ac-rec-youth-witness-hometown-athletes-shine-in-maac-championship</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Eric Rembert</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[AC Rec took local youth to Boardwalk Hall to witness former AC Viking athletes compete in the 2nd round of the MAAC Championship, showing them firsthand how hard work and dedication lead to success.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">On <strong id="">Wednesday, March 12th</strong>, <strong id="">AC Rec</strong> brought local youth to <strong id="">Boardwalk Hall</strong> to witness an exciting matchup in the <strong id="">2nd round of the MAAC Championship</strong>. The game featured <strong id="">Rider University</strong>, with former <strong id="">AC Viking</strong> <strong id="">Tank Byard</strong>, facing off against <strong id="">Quinnipiac University</strong>, where another <strong id="">AC Viking</strong> alum, <strong id="">Umar Shannon</strong>, served as <strong id="">Assistant Coach</strong>.</p><p id="">It was an incredible opportunity for the youth to see <strong id="">hometown athletes</strong> competing at the <strong id="">collegiate level</strong>, inspiring them to pursue their own dreams. <strong id="">AC Rec</strong> remains committed to providing enriching experiences that connect young people to positive role models — especially when those role models once walked the same paths they do today.</p><p id="">The event wasn’t just about basketball; it was about showing the next generation what’s possible with dedication and hard work. Watching former <strong id="">AC Vikings</strong> succeed on a bigger stage made a lasting impact on everyone in attendance.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Submitted by: Atlantic City Recreation</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/ac-rec-youth-witness-hometown-athletes-shine-in-maac-championship</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67dad9c52a5d8cc07cd1df55_485552196_18001691450758619_5847322864941691091_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City 's Senior Citizens' Enjoy a Splash of Color at Community Haven’s Paint Party
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-splash-of-color-community-havens-paint-party-success</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Senior Services wrapped up a vibrant, successful Paint Party at Community Haven — setting the stage for warmer weather and summer vibes ahead.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id=""><strong id="">Summer nights</strong> were on everyone’s mind as <strong id="">Atlantic City Senior Services</strong> hosted a vibrant and <strong id="">hugely successful Paint Party</strong> at <strong id="">Community Haven</strong>. Seniors came together to express their creativity, connect with friends, and welcome the thought of <strong id="">warmer weather</strong> with colorful masterpieces.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1390px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1390px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d989ff32b36fece9b8a1a3_Screenshot%202025-03-18%20225816.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Photos by Elizabeth Trigg</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Atlantic City Senior Citizens' enjoyed a colorful event at Community Haven. The seniors were provided a fun, relaxed atmosphere where participants let their imaginations flow on canvas. Laughter, conversation, and artistic energy filled the room, making it a memorable experience for all who joined.</p><p id="">The event was sponsored by Senior Services department of the City of Atlantic City as a way for seniors to connect. This gathering wasn’t just about painting — it was about fostering community spirit and embracing the joy that <strong id="">summer nights</strong> bring.</p><p id="">A heartfelt thank you to everyone who attended and made the day so special. We’re looking forward to more events that bring our seniors together for fun and friendship!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/a-splash-of-color-community-havens-paint-party-success</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d989e6aca5497b6f982ece_484448007_518619801280989_5067387443522588310_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Building Brighter Futures: Atlantic City Youth Services Carpentry Program Wrap-Up
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/building-brighter-futures-atlantic-city-youth-services-carpentry-program-wrap-up</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble, Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Youth Services successfully wrapped up its empowering carpentry program, made possible through partnerships with Arsareth Academy and the Boys and Girls Club. More opportunities are coming soon — stay tuned!
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The Atlantic City Youth Services recently wrapped up an inspiring <strong id="">carpentry program</strong>, thanks to the incredible partnership with <strong id="">Arsareth Academy</strong> and the <strong id="">Boys and Girls Club</strong>. This hands-on experience empowered local youth to learn practical skills, build confidence, and explore new opportunities in craftsmanship.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d9876d1fbd449459d97dcd_485226729_17996364773774785_7757436597978494403_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The program provided an engaging environment where participants not only developed <strong id="">carpentry techniques</strong> but also cultivated teamwork and problem-solving abilities — essential skills for future success.</p><p id="">Special thanks to our dedicated partners for making this opportunity possible and for supporting our mission to create meaningful experiences for Atlantic City’s youth.</p><p id="">Stay tuned — more exciting <strong id="">programs, events, and trips</strong> are on the horizon!</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/building-brighter-futures-atlantic-city-youth-services-carpentry-program-wrap-up</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d9875ed5b6fc6b992a8a9a_485178603_17996364809774785_5234691421932814193_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City High School’s NJROTC Shines During Annual Inspection
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-high-schools-njrotc-shines-during-annual-inspection</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City High School’s NJROTC cadets displayed impressive discipline and leadership during their Annual Inspection this week, earning praise for their outstanding performance.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">This week, Atlantic City High School proudly hosted the NJROTC Annual Inspection, showcasing the dedication and discipline of its NJROTC cadets.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d83d011afa0f6bee797aae_484311968_18220090951293165_7904701414970559219_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The event was a significant moment for the program, providing cadets the opportunity to demonstrate their hard work and precision in front of inspectors. Each student stood tall, representing the values of leadership, teamwork, and commitment instilled through the program.</p><p id="">Instructors and leaders commended the cadets for their impeccable performance, highlighting their attention to detail and professionalism during the inspection. The event served as both an evaluation and a celebration of the cadets' progress and growth throughout the year.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d83d13e43f4eff23697a88_484792366_18220090936293165_1709729808486421231_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Families, staff, and fellow students watched with pride, applauding the NJROTC’s efforts and achievements. The inspection reflected not only the students' individual growth but also the strength and unity of the entire program.</p><p id="">The Annual Inspection stood as a powerful reminder of the discipline and leadership cultivated at Atlantic City High School, setting a high standard for future cadets to follow.</p><p id="">Photos submitted by Atlantic City High School Photography Class</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-high-schools-njrotc-shines-during-annual-inspection</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d83c99641e2851e49ea9d2_484332003_18220090855293165_6313669090005775354_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Public Schools United for an Inspiring Convocation
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-united-for-an-inspiring-convocation</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Public Schools hosted a heartfelt Convocation, bringing together all district employees to celebrate achievements and strengthen their community spirit.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Atlantic City Public Schools came together for a powerful and uplifting Convocation on Friday, March 14, 2025, at Atlantic City High School. The event brought together all district employees to fellowship and celebrate the accomplishments of their colleagues.</p><p id="">The atmosphere was filled with camaraderie and pride as staff members from every department connected and reflected on the year’s achievements. It was a time to honor those who made an impact — from teachers shaping young minds to support staff ensuring the schools run smoothly.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1261px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1261px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d83ae3164918e1312e0e65_Screenshot%202025-03-17%20230827.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The event wasn’t just about recognition; it also served as a reminder of the collective dedication that fuels the district’s success. Leaders shared words of encouragement, emphasizing the importance of unity and perseverance in continuing to uplift students and the community.</p><p id="">As the event wrapped up, the room buzzed with renewed motivation and shared purpose, setting a positive tone for the rest of the school year.</p><p id="">The Convocation proved that Atlantic City Public Schools isn’t just a district — it’s a family, committed to growing and succeeding together.</p><p id="">Photos submitted by Atlantic City High School </p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-united-for-an-inspiring-convocation</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d83a59d0a3d10f554c8092_480287296_1171690898293994_6892879282282907282_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City's Youth: Chelsea Club's St. Patrick’s Day Celebration
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/creative-leprechauns-chelsea-clubs-st-patricks-day-celebration</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble, Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Chelsea Club Members celebrated St. Patrick’s Day by creating their own artistic leprechauns, blending creativity, community, and festive spirit.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">In honor of <strong id="">St. Patrick’s Day</strong>, the <strong id="">Chelsea Club Members</strong> came together to showcase their creativity. Each member designed and crafted their very own <strong id="">leprechaun</strong>, bringing the spirit of the holiday to life with vibrant colors and unique ideas.</p><p id="">The room was filled with laughter and excitement as everyone put their artistic skills to the test. From quirky hats to playful grins, each leprechaun reflected the personality and imagination of its creator.</p><p id="">This activity wasn’t just about art — it was about celebrating the joy and <strong id="">good luck</strong> that St. Patrick’s Day represents. It gave members a chance to bond, share stories, and embrace the festive spirit.</p><p id="">By the end of the event, the room was transformed into a cheerful display of handcrafted leprechauns, each one a reminder of the <strong id="">blessings</strong> and <strong id="">friendship</strong> that filled the day.</p><p id=""><strong id="">Chelsea Club’s</strong> St. Patrick’s Day celebration proved that creativity and community go hand in hand — and that sometimes, the luckiest thing of all is the joy of creating together.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/creative-leprechauns-chelsea-clubs-st-patricks-day-celebration</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d82260a4056616a41af502_Screenshot%202025-03-17%20212409.png"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Seniors Embark on a New Sewing Journey
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/stitching-success-atlantic-city-seniors-embark-on-a-new-sewing-journey</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The second Sewing Club kicked off with seniors embracing new skills under the guidance of Khadijah Wright. With two dedicated cohorts, creativity and imagination flourished.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The second 12-week <strong id="">Sewing Club</strong> officially kicked off, welcoming eager participants ready to learn and create. Led by the <strong id="">incredibly talented Khadijah Wright</strong>, this program brought together seniors excited to develop new <strong id="">skills</strong> and embrace their creative sides.</p><p id="">Both <strong id="">cohorts</strong> — meeting on <strong id="">Monday nights</strong> and <strong id="">Wednesday nights</strong> — began their journey with enthusiasm, imagining all the unique projects they could bring to life. From basic stitches to more advanced techniques, the class provided a space for seniors to <strong id="">imagine</strong> and <strong id="">create</strong> in ways they never thought possible.</p><p id="">The program proved that you’re <strong id="">never too young to learn new skills</strong>, fostering an uplifting and supportive environment where participants felt empowered to take on a new craft. Whether sewing for fun, for practical use, or to create gifts for loved ones, each attendee brought their own inspiration and ideas to the table.</p><p id="">Atlantic City Senior Services remains dedicated to providing programs that encourage lifelong <strong id="">learning</strong> and <strong id="">creativity</strong>, showing that growth and exploration have no age limit.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/stitching-success-atlantic-city-seniors-embark-on-a-new-sewing-journey</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d466ed311995427a6accb2_483565457_515438038265832_6391698147861371878_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Seniors Dive Back into Water Aerobics
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/making-waves-atlantic-city-seniors-dive-back-into-water-aerobics</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Trigg</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Water Aerobics is back, and Atlantic City’s seniors made a splash in their journey to stay healthy and active. This exciting program offered more than fitness — it brought the community together.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d465c27c599270fb9ccfad_484256265_514773908332245_712462324184924984_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id=""><strong id="">Water Aerobics</strong> made a refreshing return for Atlantic City’s senior community, bringing energy, movement, and joy back to the pool. This beloved program offered seniors a fun, low-impact way to stay <strong id="">healthy</strong> and <strong id="">active</strong>, while enjoying time with friends.</p><p id="">Participants embraced the opportunity to improve their <strong id="">strength</strong>, <strong id="">flexibility</strong>, and <strong id="">endurance</strong> — all while staying cool and comfortable in the water. The class provided a perfect balance of <strong id="">exercise</strong> and <strong id="">entertainment</strong>, proving that fitness can be both effective and enjoyable at any age.</p><p id="">Beyond the physical benefits, the program fostered <strong id="">community connection</strong>, encouraging seniors to engage with one another and build lasting friendships. The return of <strong id="">water aerobics</strong> wasn’t just about fitness — it was about creating an uplifting and supportive environment.</p><p id="">Atlantic City Senior Services remains committed to promoting <strong id="">health</strong> and <strong id="">well-being</strong> for our older residents, and the enthusiasm shown by our seniors reminds us how important these programs are for both body and spirit.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/making-waves-atlantic-city-seniors-dive-back-into-water-aerobics</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d465cbdd9ec061e17b65da_484098109_514773564998946_7098160448408559724_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Cooking Up Healthier Habits: Atlantic City's First Nutrition & Cooking Class
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/cooking-up-healthier-habits-atlantic-citys-first-nutrition-cooking-class</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tre Smith</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Residents of Atlantic City Townehouse took part in the city’s first Nutrition & Cooking class, learning healthy eating tips and enjoying a freshly prepared, nutritious meal.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Atlantic City celebrated the success of its <strong id="">first Nutrition &amp; Cooking class</strong> at <strong id="">Atlantic City Townehouse</strong>, where residents gathered for an engaging introduction to <strong id="">nutrition</strong>. Participants learned the importance of <strong id="">building a balanced plate</strong> and explored ways to make <strong id="">healthier food choices</strong> — empowering them to take control of their well-being through better eating habits.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d4611f431ef078dd1f8e5a_483998898_660278866678163_5786858952276850329_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The highlight of the class featured a live cooking demonstration. The instructor prepared a <strong id="">delicious pot of broccoli and cheddar soup</strong>, proving that <strong id="">nutritious meals</strong> can be both <strong id="">simple</strong> and <strong id="">flavorful</strong>. Residents not only enjoyed the meal but also gained practical tips on how to recreate healthy dishes in their own kitchens.</p><p id="">This event was more than just a cooking class — it was an opportunity to foster <strong id="">community connections</strong> and <strong id="">health-conscious habits</strong>. The hands-on approach made nutrition education accessible and enjoyable for all participants, setting the stage for future sessions filled with <strong id="">fun, food, and learning</strong>.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1440px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1440px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d46135e834aa07567fa112_483526633_660278773344839_999099208544933889_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">A heartfelt thanks goes out to <strong id="">The Community FoodBank of New Jersey</strong> and <strong id="">Atlantic City Townehouse</strong> for partnering to make this event possible. Their collaboration helped turn this class into an impactful experience for the community.</p><p id="">With the first class a success, excitement is already building for the next one. Each session aims to continue empowering residents with practical skills and knowledge to lead healthier, more balanced lives — one meal at a time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/cooking-up-healthier-habits-atlantic-citys-first-nutrition-cooking-class</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d460f7e038e246b0c27b71_483526628_660278876678162_6556834935512870367_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Youth Services’ Girl Scout Club Reaches Sweet Success
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-youth-services-girl-scout-club-reaches-sweet-success</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish, Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Youth Services' Girl Scout Club achieved an impressive milestone, selling over 100 cookies — a true testament to their teamwork and dedication.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Youth Services</strong> <strong id="">Girl Scout Club</strong> proudly surpassed a major milestone, selling <strong id="">over 100 cookies</strong>! The girls’ hard work, dedication, and team spirit made this achievement possible, showcasing their commitment to both their club and their community.</p><p id="">Throughout the cookie sales, the girls demonstrated <strong id="">entrepreneurial skills</strong>, <strong id="">teamwork</strong>, and <strong id="">perseverance</strong> — valuable lessons that extend beyond fundraising. Each sale contributed to supporting their club’s activities, encouraging the girls to build confidence while working toward a shared goal.</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1388px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1388px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d45d6787d23b2b84472ff1_Screenshot%202025-03-15%20004300.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">The success of the Girl Scout Club reflected the power of community support and the girls’ determination to make a difference. Their efforts inspired not only fellow club members but also the entire Atlantic City community.</p><p id="">Atlantic City Youth Services celebrated this impressive accomplishment, acknowledging the girls' resilience and positive spirit in reaching this sweet success.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-youth-services-girl-scout-club-reaches-sweet-success</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d45c80db20f4ec86f9da78_483461551_17995781183774785_1026809663247054305_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City’s Small Business Academy Empowers Aspiring Entrepreneurs
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-citys-small-business-academy-empowers-aspiring-entrepreneurs</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The City of Atlantic City’s Small Business Academy equipped aspiring entrepreneurs with essential skills to launch their own businesses, fostering economic growth and community empowerment.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">City of Atlantic City - Government Small Business Academy</strong> successfully kicked off its first session last week, providing <strong id="">Atlantic City residents</strong> with the tools and knowledge needed to <strong id="">jumpstart their entrepreneurial journey</strong>. The program focused on <strong id="">teaching participants</strong> the essential steps to <strong id="">launch their own small business</strong>, fostering innovation and economic growth within the community.</p><p id="">‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:2048px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="2048px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d43758fb625aa5b550185c_484869172_961478886166581_4851560489548107328_n.jpg" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">Residents engaged in practical lessons designed to guide them through business planning, financial management, and marketing strategies, equipping them with the confidence and skills to turn their ideas into reality. The academy aimed to empower future business owners by offering hands-on guidance from industry experts and local leaders.</p><p id="">For those interested in free programs like the Small Business Academy, the City of Atlantic City continues to offer valuable resources to support local entrepreneurs. Bruce Weekes, Assistant Director of Economic Development, remains available to help residents explore new opportunities and access vital support for their business ventures.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-citys-small-business-academy-empowers-aspiring-entrepreneurs</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d437646e1fc6cbdc60ba07_484391367_961478966166573_1357948199340904891_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Anti-Violence Division’s Job Fair Supports Over 600 Job Seekers
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-anti-violence-divisions-job-fair-supports-over-600-job-seekers</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nefertiti Hathaway</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Atlantic City Anti-Violence Division’s Job Fair connected over 600 job seekers with local businesses, providing immediate job offers, interviews, and career development workshops to support economic empowerment and reduce violence.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Anti-Violence Division’s Job Fair</strong>, held on <strong id="">March 11, 2025</strong>, at the <strong id="">All Wars Memorial Building</strong>, successfully connected <strong id="">over 600 individuals</strong> with <strong id="">40 local companies</strong>. Job seekers, aged <strong id="">18 and older</strong>, engaged in <strong id="">on-the-spot interviews</strong> with employers, including <strong id="">Atlantic City casinos</strong>, <strong id="">local dining establishments</strong>, and <strong id="">area businesses</strong>. Some participants <strong id="">received immediate job offers</strong>, while many others secured <strong id="">follow-up interviews</strong>, creating valuable opportunities for employment.</p><p id="">In addition to employer connections, attendees participated in <strong id="">resume and interview workshops</strong> led by the <strong id="">City of Atlantic City’s Human Resources Department</strong>. These workshops aimed to equip job seekers with essential career development skills, enhancing their chances of long-term success.</p><p id="">The event was made possible through partnerships with the <strong id="">Atlantic County Probation Department</strong>, <strong id="">Atlantic/Cape May Superior Court System</strong>, and <strong id="">Volunteers of America</strong>. The <strong id="">Anti-Violence Division</strong> designed the job fair to <strong id="">reduce violence</strong> by promoting <strong id="">economic empowerment</strong> and <strong id="">creating opportunities</strong> — a vital step in supporting Atlantic City residents in achieving a brighter future.</p><p id=""><strong id="">One Neighborhood Evolution</strong>, the driving force behind the division, remains committed to uplifting the community, particularly its youth. Earlier this month, the organization provided a group of <strong id="">Atlantic City children</strong> the chance to attend the <strong id="">Lamont Roach vs. Gervonta “Tank” Davis</strong> boxing match at the <strong id="">Barclays Center</strong> in <strong id="">Brooklyn, New York</strong>, broadening their horizons through unique experiences.</p><p id="">Looking ahead, the <strong id="">Anti-Violence Division</strong> plans to host a <strong id="">Lift Warrant event</strong> on <strong id="">April 9th</strong>, offering individuals with <strong id="">outstanding court matters</strong> in <strong id="">Atlantic City Joint</strong> and <strong id="">Atlantic County Central Municipal Courts</strong> the chance to resolve legal issues by meeting with a judge — continuing their mission to empower and support the community.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-anti-violence-divisions-job-fair-supports-over-600-job-seekers</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d43456b22e9330bbd58066_483546907_960978616216608_1317639402332189422_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Youth: Young Scientists Shine at Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. School Complex Science Fair
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/young-scientists-shine-at-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-school-complex-science-fair</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. School Complex recently held its annual science fair, showcasing students' creativity, innovation, and scientific talent — from environmental experiments to a unique science-based vending machine.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. School Complex,</strong> an elementary school in Atlantic CIty, recently hosted its annual <strong id="">science fair</strong>, inspiring students from <strong id="">grades 3 through 8</strong> to explore, experiment, and innovate. Led by <strong id="">Principal Jodi Burroughs</strong> and <strong id="">Superintendent of Schools Dr. La'Quetta S. Small</strong>, the event encouraged young learners to dive into the <strong id="">scientific method</strong>, fostering creativity and critical thinking.</p><p id="">“It was great, and it was a great opportunity for kids to show what they’ve learned and what they have been thinking about in science,” <strong id="">Principal Burroughs</strong> shared.</p><p id="">Students showcased an impressive range of projects — from classic models like <strong id="">volcanoes</strong> and <strong id="">water cycles</strong> to inventive, out-of-the-box creations like a <strong id="">science-based vending machine,</strong> which stood out as a first for the fair. <strong id="">Burroughs</strong> praised the students' <strong id="">innovation</strong>, highlighting how they embraced ideas “that aren’t normally done.”<br>‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1304px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1304px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d1b4802ec7251f5f351562_Screenshot%202025-03-13%20001632.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">This year’s theme, <strong id="">"Environmental Science in Action,"</strong> guided students to focus their experiments on <strong id="">fixing the environment</strong>. <strong id="">Tamara Mingo</strong>, <strong id="">5th grade science teacher</strong> and <strong id="">word study instructor</strong>, applauded the young scientists' efforts to tackle environmental issues, showing how science can make a real-world impact.</p><p id="">The fair not only celebrated the students' impressive <strong id="">scientific achievements</strong> but also nurtured a <strong id="">spirit of inquiry and lifelong learning</strong>. The event served as a powerful reminder of the <strong id="">importance of science education</strong>, empowering students to think critically and embrace the endless possibilities of discovery.</p><p id="">For a closer look at the students' incredible work, check out the <strong id="">photo gallery</strong>: <a target="_new" href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/cL21gcNktrSM7faF7" id="">https://photos.app.goo.gl/cL21gcNktrSM7faF7</a></p><p id="">Source from: <a href="https://www.acboe.org/site/default.aspx?PageType=3&ModuleInstanceID=7127&ViewID=7b97f7ed-8e5e-4120-848f-a8b4987d588f&RenderLoc=0&FlexDataID=23380&PageID=5945&fbclid=IwY2xjawI-jg9leHRuA2FlbQIxMAABHfcJE0OTdsZgzOGpKVWU416tUHs3woUB768hEFI2yd8HqVFZWdANYf_Jtg_aem_GvvJ0mbaa9BemBH_L8gwAw" id="">Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. School Complex Hosts Inspiring Science Fair</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/young-scientists-shine-at-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-school-complex-science-fair</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d1b464b7657198f8ee5da5_IMG_6205%20(1).jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Mayor Small Announced New Criteria for Third Year of $3M Scholarship Program for Atlantic City Residents
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-announced-new-criteria-for-third-year-of-3m-scholarship-program-for-atlantic-city-residents</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Mayor Marty Small, Sr. announced new eligibility criteria for the third year of his $3M scholarship program, awarding 100 scholarships worth up to $10,000 each to Atlantic City residents. The program expanded this year to support more students, including trade school applicants and graduates from other schools accepting Atlantic City students.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Mayor Marty Small, Sr. and the <strong id="">“Mayor Marty Small, Sr. Scholarship”</strong> committee announced exciting new details for the third year of the program, providing 100 scholarships worth up to $10,000 each to eligible Atlantic City residents.</p><p id="">First introduced in 2023, the “Mayor Marty Small, Sr. Scholarship” represented a three-year commitment of up to $3 million — with $1 million awarded each year. In the first two years, eligibility was limited to Atlantic City residents who recently graduated from Atlantic City High School (ACHS) or were current college students who previously graduated from ACHS. This year, eligibility expanded to include residents who will graduate this spring or previously graduated from ACHS or another school accepting Atlantic City students. The scholarships supported graduating high school seniors accepted to accredited higher educational institutions, current college freshmen, sophomores, juniors, graduate and doctoral students, and prospective trade school students.</p><p id="">Scholarship recipients received half of the funds for the fall 2025 semester and the remaining half for the spring 2026 semester. The selection process was conducted by a committee of city employees and community members, excluding Mayor Small from the decision-making process. Students who previously applied and continued to meet the eligibility criteria were encouraged to reapply. Funding for the $3 million scholarship came from the Addressing Educational Disparity category of American Rescue Plan funds allocated to Atlantic City. </p><p id="">‍<strong id="">Completed applications were due by 4:00 PM EST on Monday, April 7, 2025</strong>.</p><h3 id=""><em id="">For more details or to apply:<br></em>➡ <a href="https://www.acnj.gov/.../Mayor-Marty-Small-Sr-Scholarship...">APPLICATION LINK</a><br>➡ <a href="https://www.acnj.gov/.../mayor-small-announces-new..." id="">More Information on Criteria and Eligibility</a></h3>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/mayor-small-announced-new-criteria-for-third-year-of-3m-scholarship-program-for-atlantic-city-residents</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67d187c9275aca1caf2c9661_483675219_959411879706615_6617899396524326335_n.jpg"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Honoring Atlantic City Police Officer Thomas McMeekin Jr.: 20 Years of Remembrance
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-officer-thomas-mcmeekin-jr-20-years-of-remembrance</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Every March 4, the Atlantic City community gathers at the intersection of Chelsea and Atlantic avenues to pay tribute to Officer Thomas McMeekin Jr., a dedicated member of the Atlantic City Police Department whose legacy continues to be honored two decades after his passing.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">Every March 4, the Atlantic City community gathers at the intersection of Chelsea and Atlantic avenues to pay tribute to Officer Thomas McMeekin Jr., a dedicated member of the Atlantic City Police Department whose legacy continues to be honored two decades after his passing.</p><p id="">Officer McMeekin, a five-year veteran of the force, tragically lost his life at just 28 years old after being struck while directing traffic at an accident scene on March 3, 2005. The following day, his passing left a lasting impact on his family, colleagues, and the city he served.</p><p id="">To commemorate his sacrifice, friends, family, and fellow officers come together each year at the very spot where he was struck—now named in his honor. Following the ceremony, the group gathers at the Irish Pub, a long-standing tradition that allows those who knew him to share memories and celebrate the life he lived.</p><p id="">Officer McMeekin came from a family deeply rooted in public service, with both his father and brother serving as Atlantic City firefighters. His dedication to protecting and serving the community remains an inspiration, and his memory continues to be a guiding light for those who wear the badge.</p><p id="">As the city marks 20 years since his passing, the annual tribute ensures that his legacy lives on—not just in the hearts of those who knew him, but in the spirit of service that defines Atlantic City’s law enforcement community.</p><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Photo Source:&nbsp;Jen Miller McMeekin Facebook</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/honoring-officer-thomas-mcmeekin-jr-20-years-of-remembrance</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67cf10b524400883d609406a_Screenshot%202025-03-11%20001237.png"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
State Wrestling Tournament Attendees Take Notice: Atlantic City’s Safer, Cleaner, and Stronger Than Ever
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/state-wrestling-tournament-attendees-take-notice-atlantic-citys-safer-cleaner-and-stronger-than-ever</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 20:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ziggy Chau</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City has long been a destination for world-class events, and with continued investments in safety and infrastructure, its reputation is evolving. Thanks to the Atlantic City Police Department, Chief James Sarkos, and the leadership of Mayor Marty Small Sr., the city is taking proactive steps to ensure that residents and visitors alike feel secure.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">This past weekend, <strong id="">the New Jersey State Interscholastic Athletic Association (NJSIAA) Wrestling Tournament</strong> brought thousands of athletes, families, and fans to Atlantic City, marking one of the most anticipated sporting events in the region. As competitors took to the mats inside Jim Whelan Boardwalk Hall, visitors also enjoyed everything the city had to offer—from its casinos and restaurants to its renowned Boardwalk.</p><p id="">A growing sentiment among attendees was clear: <strong id="">Atlantic City felt safer and cleaner than ever</strong>.</p><p id="">‍</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">A City Committed to Safety &amp; Progress</strong></h3><p id="">In recent years, <strong id="">Atlantic City has made significant strides</strong> in improving public safety and reshaping perceptions. Under the leadership of <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Chief James Sarkos</strong> and <strong id="">Mayor Marty Small Sr.</strong>, crime in the city <strong id="">decreased by over 8% in 2024</strong>, while <strong id="">calls for service dropped 16%</strong> and <strong id="">arrests rose by 20.7%</strong>. These improvements have strengthened public confidence in the city, with many visitors noticing the <strong id="">increased police presence and enhanced atmosphere</strong>.</p><p id="">The hiring of former Pleasantville Police Chief Sean Riggin as Atlantic City’s new Public Safety Director—a role not filled since 2013—demonstrated the city’s ongoing commitment to making <strong id="">public safety a top priority</strong>. The <strong id="">Atlantic City Police Department (ACPD)</strong> played a critical role in these efforts, ensuring that high-profile events like the state wrestling tournament were well-patrolled and secure. Officers stationed in and around Boardwalk Hall provided a reassuring presence for residents and visitors alike.</p><p id="">The<a href="https://pressofatlanticcity.com/news/local/crime-courts/article_9b2e45c2-fb78-11ef-bb41-afebcbfb585b.html" id=""> <em id="">Press of Atlantic City</em></a> recently reported that many attendees of this year’s tournament <strong id="">noticed the city’s positive changes</strong>. One visitor, Joe Lewis of Cranford, Union County, shared that although he once had a negative perception of the city based on past reports, the statistics showing crime reduction have changed his outlook. <em id="">“That’s the type of stuff people need to hear,”</em> he said, emphasizing that as Atlantic City continues to improve, so will its public image.</p><p id="">‍</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">Economic Boost &amp; Tourism Impact</strong></h3><p id="">Beyond the competition itself, the tournament remained a significant driver of economic activity in the city. The event contributed over $3.7 million in customer spending, with 71% of attendees spending more than $200 at local businesses. Many visitors opted to stay at Boardwalk hotels and casinos, taking advantage of the walkability, nightlife, and entertainment options.</p><p id="">According to that recent article, longtime tournament attendee Gary Hutchinson makes multiple trips to Atlantic City each year, both for the wrestling tournament and summer getaways. He, like many others, noticed the city’s efforts to maintain well-lit streets, a stronger police presence, and an overall improved atmosphere. Visitors reported feeling safer and more comfortable navigating the Boardwalk and surrounding areas, with enhanced lighting and law enforcement visibility contributing to an improved experience.</p><p id="">‍</p><h3 id=""><strong id="">A Changing Narrative</strong></h3><p id="">Atlantic City has long been a destination for world-class events, and with continued investments in safety and infrastructure, its reputation is evolving. Thanks to the Atlantic City Police Department, Chief James Sarkos, and the leadership of Mayor Marty Small Sr., the city is taking proactive steps to ensure that residents and visitors alike feel secure.</p><p id="">With crime rates trending downward and new efforts to maintain safety and cleanliness, more visitors are recognizing the positive changes. As Lewis noted in <em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em>, <em id="">when people hear the facts, their perception of the city begins to shift.</em></p><p id="">And for those who may still be skeptical, Hutchinson offered this perspective in <a href="https://pressofatlanticcity.com/news/local/crime-courts/article_9b2e45c2-fb78-11ef-bb41-afebcbfb585b.html" id=""><em id="">The Press of Atlantic City</em>:</a><br><em id="">“Just give the city a chance. Sure, it might have the perception of being unsafe, but there is also a lot of good here, and I know city officials are working hard to improve its image. I’ve seen the improvements firsthand.”</em></p><p id="">The 2025 NJSIAA State Wrestling Tournament showcased more than just top-tier competition—it <strong id="">highlighted Atlantic City’s progress</strong> and <strong id="">reinforced its status as a premier destination for major events</strong>. With a <strong id="">stronger, safer city taking shape</strong>, Atlantic City continues to <strong id="">prove that its best days are still ahead</strong>.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/state-wrestling-tournament-attendees-take-notice-atlantic-citys-safer-cleaner-and-stronger-than-ever</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67cf1bb1d83264a5bd804e17_Screenshot%202025-03-11%20010513.png"/>
</item>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[
Atlantic City Public Schools Celebrated Read Across America
]]></title>
<link>https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-celebrated-read-across-america</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 19:00:00 EST</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tasha Devonish, Christina Noble</dc:creator>
<description><![CDATA[The Atlantic City Public Schools celebrated Read Across America with special events, guest readers, and literacy initiatives. Students were encouraged to embrace the joy of reading, fostering confidence and a love for literature that will last a lifetime.
]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="">The <strong id="">Atlantic City Public Schools</strong> embraced the joy of reading as they participated in <strong id="">Read Across America</strong>. Superintendent <strong id="">Dr. La’Quetta S. Small</strong> visited <strong id="">Texas Avenue School</strong> on March 6, 2025, where she shared her love for literature with students. Sitting before <strong id="">Rohima Begun’s second-grade class</strong>, Dr. Small read the book <strong id="">“I Am Enough”</strong> by Grace Byers, encouraging students to embrace their individuality and self-worth.</p><p id="">As Dr. Small read, students listened attentively and reflected on the story’s message. <strong id="">Aryan Camarillo</strong>, a second-grade student, took the lesson to heart, sharing, <strong id="">“If it doesn’t work the first time, try a second time.”</strong> The event reinforced the power of perseverance and self-confidence through literature.</p><p id="">‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1125px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1125px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67cf05a99f2a2f7b22611ee6_Screenshot%202025-03-10%20232411.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">‍</p><p id="">Throughout the district, schools hosted various literacy-focused activities, including <strong id="">read-a-thons, spelling bees, and visits from community members</strong>. <strong id="">Texas Avenue School Principal Lina Gil</strong> emphasized the importance of promoting literacy in a fun and engaging way, while guest readers such as <strong id="">Board of Education President Shay Steele, Geoffrey Dorsey, and Dr. Small</strong> read to students at <strong id="">New York Avenue School and Brighton Avenue School</strong>.</p><p id="">At <strong id="">Sovereign Avenue School</strong>, Media Specialist <strong id="">Kimberly Shick</strong> organized a celebration featuring readings by <strong id="">Charles and Randi Barbin of the Dunes Art Gallery</strong>, who highlighted the importance of <strong id="">physical books</strong> in today’s digital world. Former <strong id="">NFL player Keith Hunter</strong> visited <strong id="">Chelsea Heights School</strong>, reminding students of the value of <strong id="">active listening</strong> in both academics and life.</p><p id="">‍</p><figure id="" class="w-richtext-figure-type-image w-richtext-align-fullwidth" style="max-width:1387px" data-rt-type="image" data-rt-align="fullwidth" data-rt-max-width="1387px"><div id=""><img src="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67cf05b91fdbaf3947328c53_Screenshot%202025-03-10%20232403.png" loading="lazy" alt="__wf_reserved_inherit" width="auto" height="auto" id=""></div></figure><p id="">‍</p><p id=""><strong id="">Read Across America</strong> is more than a one-day event—it is a movement designed to foster a lifelong love of reading. By participating in this initiative, <strong id="">Atlantic City Public Schools</strong> reaffirmed their commitment to literacy and student success, ensuring that every child has the opportunity to explore the world through books.</p><p id="">‍</p>
]]></content:encoded>
<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatdayatlanticcity.com/news/atlantic-city-public-schools-celebrated-read-across-america</guid>
<media:thumbnail url="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/67527a6c8f757cda3e333e95/67cf05880b0bc7309b8cb93a_480301247_1165797295550021_1188699629363711368_n.jpg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>